s
s
n
n
.
。
c
c
g
g
h
h
a
ある
n
n
u
の
pull
引く
cut
切る
areas
エリア
so
それで
curbs
縁石
w
の
f
f
n
n
w
の
o
○
2018 Governor's Banquet, Science Popularization Lectures and Speakers in October
2018年10月知事晩餐会、科学普及講演会および講演者
We ask the Director of No Impulse of the Secretariat of the Court to host for us
裁判所事務局のノー・インパルス局長に司会をお願いします。
Okay, thank you all colleagues present
はい、ご出席の同僚の皆様、ありがとうございました
Or interested in popular science
またはポピュラーサイエンスに興味がある
There is still a little drizzle outside in this early autumn season
初秋のこの季節、外はまだ小雨が降っています
Still willing to take off the tired mood after a day of work
一日の仕事の後に疲れた気分を取り除きたい
I am also willing to come to the Institute of Chinese Studies to listen to lectures on popular science
また、中国研究所に行き、大衆科学に関する講義を聞きたいと思っています。
Today's speech is given by the deputy director of our Institute of Astronomy and Astrophysics
本日の講演は当天文・天体物理研究所の副所長が行います。
Researcher Wang Xiangyu, who is also the deputy director
研究者の王祥宇氏、自ら副所長
he came to give a keynote speech
彼は基調講演をするために来た
The eyes of astronomers who make astronomers
天文学者を作る天文学者の目
The development of Jianduan astronomy
建端天文学の発展
What about Mr. Wang, he and I are in fact the black hole this time
王さんはどうでしょうか。今回は彼と私が実はブラックホールなのです
because of the black hole
ブラックホールのせいで
So have more close interaction with him
だから彼ともっと緊密に交流しましょう
He is a very personable, very gentle person
とても人柄が良くて、とても優しい人です
I took a closer look at his profile
彼のプロフィールを詳しく調べてみた
He himself graduated from the Institute of Electronics of our Jiaotong University
彼自身も交通大学電子工学院を卒業しました。
After he graduated with a Ph.D.
彼は博士号を取得して卒業した後、
joined our newly established
新設された当社に加わりました
Astronomical Institute of Astrophysics
天体物理学天文研究所
Currently a researcher and deputy director of our astronomical institute
現在、当天文研究所研究員兼副所長
he is central university
彼は中央大学です
He is also an adjunct professor at the Central Space Science Institute
彼は中央宇宙科学研究所の非常勤教授でもあります。
and director of the East Asia Observatory
東アジア天文台所長ら
His research specialization was developed in Astronomical Rituals
彼の研究専門分野は天文儀式で発展しました。
small solar system bodies
太陽系の小さな天体
Infrared detection
赤外線検出
dendrite gold
デンドライトゴールド
The teacher told me that I don't know what astronomical Shulei gold is
先生は私に、天文学的なシュレイゴールドが何なのか分からないと言いました。
his research looks real
彼の研究は本物のようです
really great
ほんとうに素晴らしい
It is currently the only one in the astronomical institute
現在、天文研究所にある唯一のものです。
Personnel who can engage in the development of visible light and infrared rays
可視光・赤外線の開発に携われる人材
Dominated four international telescopes over the years
長年にわたって4つの国際望遠鏡を独占
Instrument R&D Equipment
計測器研究開発装置
It is also a Sino-US acting project
これも中米の演技プロジェクトです
And one of the hosts of the Neptune Celestial Show Mind Project
ネプチューン・セレスティアル・ショー・マインド・プロジェクトの主催者の一人でもある
It conducts research on the evolution history of the solar system
太陽系の進化の歴史を研究しています
At the same time participated in the research and development of Japanese scientific satellites
同時に日本の科学衛星の研究開発にも参加
Also completed research globe
研究地球儀も完成
Electron Analyzer of the Magnetosphere
磁気圏の電子分析装置
To be fair I don't even know what that means.
正直に言うと、それが何を意味するのかさえわかりません。
But we may ask Mr. Wang to explain later
ただし、後で王氏に説明してもらうかもしれません
it is currently leading a team
現在チームを率いています
Entering the Next Generation of Infrared Space Telescopes
次世代の赤外線宇宙望遠鏡への参入
and the future world's largest
そして将来的には世界最大の
Instrument development for the European Visible Light Telescope
ヨーロッパ可視光望遠鏡用の機器開発
And hope to expand Taiwan astronomy
台湾の天文学を広めたい
Opportunity to participate in state-of-the-art observing equipment
最先端の観測機器に参加するチャンス
It also assists domestic manufacturers
国内メーカーもサポート
Build an automated large area detector
自動化された大面積検出器を構築する
There is also a system for camera detection
カメラ検知システムも搭載
Hopefully these astronomical instruments will resolve
これらの天文機器が解決するといいですね
It's not just about seeing the sky
ただ空を見るだけではない
It can also solve our current domestic industry
現在の国内産業も解決できる
domestic and foreign industries
国内外の産業
all the problems
すべての問題
and create some possible business opportunities
いくつかのビジネスチャンスを生み出す可能性があります
It's a little bit windy outside today
今日は外がもっと浮いています
english fat
英語の脂肪
But if you are interested
でも興味があるなら
I don't know everyone last Saturday
先週の土曜日はみんな知りません
Have you ever come to see go away open
オープンアウェイを見に来たことはありますか
Everyone can also go to the Humanities Museum
誰でも人文博物館に行くことができます
the stairs
階段
can see us a black hole
私たちにブラックホールが見える
This year is our Central Plains
今年は私たちのセントラルプレーンズです
a very important year
とても重要な年
Our team in Taiwan and the world
台湾と世界の私たちのチーム
we found
私たちは一緒に発見しました
Black hole photographed for the first time
ブラックホールを初めて撮影
confirmed the black hole
ブラックホールを確認した
If you look carefully
よく見ると
It's actually very, very difficult
それは実際にはとてもとても難しいことです
if you look at it now
今見たら
that picture looks
その写真は見えます
not very clear
あまり明確ではない
Then I was last Saturday
それから私は先週の土曜日に
I just heard
今聞いた
How difficult is it to photograph that black hole?
そのブラックホールを写真に撮るのはどれくらい難しいですか?
after everyone listened
みんなが聞いた後
I just discovered my admiration for that Teacher Wang
私は今、王先生への憧れを発見しました。
deep in my heart
私の心の奥深くに
how difficult that is
それはどれほど難しいことか
As you can imagine, it's probably from New York
ご想像のとおり、おそらくニューヨークからのものです
to see in los angeles
ロサンゼルスで見る
a golf ball
ゴルフボール
a small groove on the top
上部に小さな溝
You can imagine how difficult it would be
それがどれほど難しいか想像できるでしょう
So it's no wonder we're developing everything so cutting-edge
したがって、私たちがあらゆるものを最先端のものとして開発しているのも不思議ではありません
So let me think about it
それで、考えさせてください
Seeing Los Angeles from New York
ニューヨークからロサンゼルスを見る
A small groove in a golf ball
ゴルフボールの小さな溝
how did it work
それはどうでしたか？
Next, we warmly welcome Mr. Wang
次に、王氏を温かく歓迎します。
Come help us analyze
分析に協力してください
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you Director
ありがとうディレクター
goodbye
さようなら
I've actually been playing this video before starting my talk
実は講演を始める前にこのビデオを再生していたのです
Then this is actually everyone's image
じゃあこれが実はみんなのイメージなんです
I use this little machine
私はこの小さな機械を使っています
This is the instrument we developed ourselves
これは私たちが自分たちで開発した楽器です
But in fact, this is still far from most astronomical instruments.
しかし実際には、これはほとんどの天文機器からはまだ程遠いです。
This is the one we developed for Zhongshan Science people.
これは私たちが中山科学の人々のために開発したものです。
a new chair used on satellites
人工衛星で使用される新しい椅子
it can do very fast tracking
非常に高速な追跡が可能です
Know the current attitude of my satellite
私の衛星の現在の姿勢を知る
The current attitude of artificial satellites is a thing for navigation
現在の人工衛星の考え方はナビゲーションのためのものです
Then I want to use this small example to tell you
それでは、この小さな例を使ってお話したいと思います
In addition to astronomical instruments
天文機器以外にも
In fact, there are many other related applications
実際、他にも多くの関連アプリケーションがあります
Then I will start my speech today
それでは今日のスピーチを始めます
Director Wu just introduced the topic of today's speech
呉所長が今日のスピーチのテーマを紹介しました
introduce everyone
みんなを紹介する
Have some knowledge about the astronomical instruments behind the development of it
開発の背後にある天文機器についてある程度の知識がある
Where is its application and its difficulty
その応用と難しさはどこにあるのか
in this first page
この最初のページで
In fact, I put a picture of the moon
実は月の写真も載せてみました
This photo of the moon was actually taken by my daughter
この月の写真は実際に娘が撮ったものです
She took a digital camera
彼女はデジタルカメラを持って行きました
It's the fried moon
揚げた月だよ
just push it down
ただ押し下げるだけです
Then you will see full image
すると全体画像が表示されます
In fact, the current technology is honestly very advanced.
実際、現在の技術は非常に進んでいます。
So in fact, many times
それで実際に何度も
If you are looking for a place to construct a case
案件を構築できる場所をお探しの場合
You go to the right place in the sky to shoot
空の適切な場所に行って撮影します
you can shoot this
これを撃ってもいいよ
It's still a very beautiful image of the Milky Way
相変わらずとても美しい天の川の画像です
then you may think
それからあなたは思うかもしれません
Hey, since you can just go and buy a digital camera
ねえ、デジタルカメラを買いに行ってもいいから
You just shot it so well
とても上手に撮れましたね
So why do you want the school to do it yourself?
では、なぜ学校が自分たちでやろうとするのでしょうか？
I'll just go around and find someone to get my equipment out.
あちこち行って、私の機材を取り出してくれる人を探します。
that's actually
それは実際に
I also said today that I hope that after listening to
今日も言いましたが、聞いた後はそうなってほしいと思います。
just talk about why
理由を話してください
We have to spend so much effort on the development of astronomical instruments
私たちは天文機器の開発に多大な労力を費やさなければなりません
Mainly there are very main reasons why we have to do it ourselves
私たちが自分たちでやらなければならない主な理由は次のとおりです
It's just that you can't buy it
ただ買えないだけだよ
Because you can find these cameras in the market
これらのカメラは市場で見つけることができるため、
or imaging systems, in fact, they are all fixed specifications
または画像システム、実際にはすべて固定仕様です
But we astronomers special binoculars
しかし、私たち天文学者は特別な双眼鏡を持っています
In fact, they all have different designs
実は全部違うデザインなんです
So each binocular has its own characteristics
このように、それぞれの双眼鏡には独自の特徴があります。
kind of like your own eyes
自分の目のようなもの
If everyone's eyes are short-sighted
みんなの目が近視なら
You can't wear someone else's glasses
他人のメガネをかけることはできません
so i can see clearly
だから私ははっきりと見ることができます
The same goes for every binocular, it has its own designed focal length
すべての双眼鏡にも同様のことが言え、独自に設計された焦点距離があります。
In addition to this focal length, it has the so-called phase difference in the system
この焦点距離に加えて、システム内にいわゆる位相差があります。
so it's hard for you to get between binoculars
だから双眼鏡の間に入るのは難しい
I'm the one who moves this department around
この部門を動かしているのは私です
you can get the same effect
同じ効果が得られます
In addition, in fact, every binocular
さらに、実際には、すべての双眼鏡
it all wants to have its own character
すべてが独自のキャラクターを持ちたがっている
Make the best science in the world
世界で最高の科学を作る
So I'm going to achieve the best of this
だから私はこれで最高のものを達成するつもりです
We speak the words of the best potency
私たちは最高の効力を持つ言葉を話します
then i will do it myself
それなら自分でやります
Of course, another reason is that
もちろん、もう一つの理由としては、
In fact, if you are really rich
実際、本当にお金持ちであれば、
You can definitely find Guangshi to do it for you
あなたの代わりにやってくれるGuangshiがきっと見つかります
It's just that most scientists are really poor
ほとんどの科学者は本当に貧しいだけです
Our funds are usually picked again and again.
私たちのファンドは通常、何度も選ばれます。
So everyone becomes self-developed
だから誰もが自己成長する
Then let the research of this astronomy department
それではこの天文学部の研究をさせてください
become a very special field of study
非常に特殊な研究分野になる
In fact, the whole world
実際、全世界が
The person engaged in the development of the first phase of this astronomy
この天文学の第一段階の開発に携わった人物
Maybe it's because we've been in touch so often
頻繁に連絡を取っているからかもしれません
probably a few thousand
おそらく数千
so it's not a huge area of ​​research
それほど大した研究分野ではありません
But it is for the study of astronomy
ただし、それは天文学の研究のためです
is a very big contribution
非常に大きな貢献です
then this is a photo
それからこれは写真です
Here's a picture of me taking this thing apart
これは私がこれを分解している写真です
actually tell you
実際に言ってください
Presumably there will be something inside an instrument
おそらく楽器の中に何かが入っているでしょう
I will introduce it in detail later
後ほど詳しくご紹介します
that this thing because it's small
これは小さいから
This is about the smallest thing we've ever made that could easily be brought here
これは私たちがこれまでに作ったものの中で、簡単にここに持ち込めるものとしては最小のものです
Basically, the instrument we developed is a big thing
基本的に、私たちが開発した機器は大きなものです
It's also very heavy, weighing several tons
重さも数トンもあるのでとても重いです
I can't bring it here for everyone to see
みんなに見てもらうためにここに持っていくことはできない
The main reason why it is necessary to make such a big thing
これほど大きなものを作る必要がある主な理由
In fact, it has a lot to do with the progress of our human technology.
実際、それは人類のテクノロジーの進歩と大きく関係しています。
Then everyone may be familiar with it
それなら誰もが知っているかもしれません
We are famous in Taiwan for the manufacture of this semiconductor
当社はこの半導体の製造で台湾では有名です
There is a well-known motorcycle listening rate in semiconductor manufacturing to tell you
半導体製造におけるオートバイの聴取率はよく知られています。
That is to say, the same area of ​​these chips can carry the number of transistors
つまり、これらのチップの同じ面積に同じ数のトランジスタを搭載できるということです。
In fact, its increasing speed is a logarithmic increase in terms of time.
実際、その増加速度は時間で言えば対数増加です。
Then this law is also applicable if you put it into the astronomy
この法則は天文学に応用した場合にも当てはまります
Everyone should know that
誰もがそれを知っているはずです
GID slightly 400 years ago
わずか400年前の性同一性障害
He was the first person to invent net access
彼はネット アクセスを発明した最初の人物でした
What was the caliber of the net inlet he invented 400 years ago?
彼が 400 年前に発明した網の入口の口径は何でしたか?
is only 2 cm
わずか2cmです
that passed 400 years
400年の時を経て
right now we
今、私たちは
Visible light network entrance with the largest aperture
最大口径の可視光ネットワーク入口
is 10 meters
10メートルです
maybe later
おそらく後で
It's 2019
2019年になりました
In about five or six years
5、6年くらいしたら
There will be one in Europe
ヨーロッパにもあるだろう
Nearly 40 meters net net entry
ネットエントリーは40メートル近く
then this is a
それならこれは
a very rapidly growing curve
非常に急速に成長する曲線
So with this astronomical
それで、この天文学的には
The caliber of this net becomes larger
この網の口径が大きくなる
Then the size of the instrument I need
次に、必要な楽器のサイズ
will also get bigger and bigger
もどんどん大きくなります
Then you may find it a little strange to hear this.
そうしたら、これを聞くと少し奇妙に感じるかもしれません。
Really?
本当？
The largest astronomical network
最大の天文ネットワーク
is only 10 meters
わずか10メートルです
We seem to be here all the time
私たちはいつもここにいるようです
The explosives will see that China has an eye in the sky
爆発物は中国が空に目を向けていることに気づくだろう
This sky eye is a 500-meter location
このスカイアイは500メートルの場所です
But this because it is a
しかし、これは、
We say that it is suitable for locations with relatively long radio wave fields
比較的電波の届く範囲が長いアウトドアシーンに適しているという。
it's not like what i just said
それは私が今言ったこととは違います
All the things I just said here
私が今ここで言ったことすべて
All visible light
すべての可視光
Then your TRON range is different
その場合、TRON の範囲が異なります
In fact, your application technology is also different.
実際、アプリケーション テクノロジも異なります。
So we're basically
だから私たちは基本的に
We still have to use the same standard to compare
比較するには同じ基準を使用する必要があります
same technique
同じテクニック
That's what I was talking about
それが私が話していたことです
When binoculars get bigger and bigger
双眼鏡がどんどん大きくなると
In fact, scientists still use some small tricks
実際、科学者たちは今でもいくつかの小さなトリックを使用しています
That this is the current world
ここが今の世界だということを
arguably the most famous
おそらく最も有名な
This CAC binoculars from UC
カリフォルニア大学の CAC 双眼鏡
it's a 10 meter telescope
それは10メートルの望遠鏡です
You can see that it is not a complete mirror
完全な鏡ではないことがわかります
In fact, it has a large
実際、それには大きな特徴があります
A lot of hexagons put together
六角形をたくさん組み合わせたもの
That's because scientists are doing the research and development of the binoculars
それは科学者たちが双眼鏡の研究開発を行っているからです
You slowly discovered that I have encountered a technical bottleneck
あなたは私が技術的なボトルネックに直面していることに徐々に気づきました
If I put the same big single lens
同じ大きな一眼を入れたら
while slowly expanding its size
ゆっくりとサイズを拡大しながら
I will find it very difficult to make my
自分のものを作るのはとても難しいと思います
Therefore, modern visible glasses usually use splicing technology
したがって、現代の可視ガラスは通常、スプライシング技術を使用しています
Hexagonal binoculars about one meter in length
長さ約1メートルの六角形の双眼鏡
put it together and form it into a larger binoculars
それを組み立てて大きな双眼鏡にします
This picture shows the size of the largest binoculars in the world
この写真は世界最大の双眼鏡の大きさを示しています
with its mirror image
その鏡像で
draw it all out
すべてを引き出して
It can be found that in the early days, a single lens was used to form my binoculars
初期の頃、私の双眼鏡を構成するために単一のレンズが使用されていたことがわかります。
That's about eight meters away.
それは約8メートル離れています。
we just stop doing this
私たちはこれをやめるだけです
Therefore, all mirrors with a caliber exceeding 8 meters often use this splicing method.
したがって、口径が8メートルを超えるすべての鏡には、この接合方法がよく使用されます。
Use a small regular mirror to go back and forth
小さな普通の鏡を使って往復する
Small lenses come and go to combine into one large lens
小さなレンズが行き来して 1 つの大きなレンズに結合します
So next in
それで次は
In the next 10 years, I expect there will be 30-meter class
今後10年以内には30メートル級が登場すると予想
Large astronomical mirrors tend to slowly
大きな天体鏡はゆっくりと動く傾向があります。
Join the ranks of this astronomical observation
天体観測の仲間入りをしましょう
Of course these observations
もちろんこれらの観察は
It requires very sophisticated astronomical instruments
非常に洗練された天文機器が必要です
so that you can use
使えるように
In order to really put the wide mouth mirror
広口ミラーを実際に取り付けるには
Observation ability of the mirror
鏡の観察力
play it out
遊んでみる
So advances in observational astronomy
観測天文学の進歩
In fact, it has a lot to do with the development of astronomical instruments.
実は、それは天文機器の開発と大きく関係しています。
On the contrary, if you can master the technology of these astronomical instruments
逆に、これらの天文機器の技術を使いこなすことができれば、
you can master observation
観察をマスターできる
Suspect of the Department of Astronomy
天文学部の容疑者
So Central Academy of Astronomy
中央天文学アカデミー
we are at
私たちは〜にて
When we established the institute more than 20 years ago, we
20年以上前に研究所を設立したとき、私たちは
Sure
確定
We are doing science at the same time
私たちは同時に科学も行っています
research and development of the Department of Astronomy
天文学部の研究開発
that in the past twenty years
過去20年間のこと
We also put a lot of effort into
私たちも力を入れています
to develop
開発する
and
と
Improve our astronomy department
天文学部を改善する
this ability
この能力
Then I thought about our current
それから私たちの今について考えました
Scientific achievements are similar to those of our astronomy department
科学的成果は天文学部と同様です
developed this
これを開発した
result
結果
It can be said that it matches quite well.
かなりマッチしていると言えるでしょう。
pretty good
かなり良い
That
それか
What exactly does an astronomy school want in general?
一般的に天文学学校は一体何を求めているのでしょうか？
Astronomy schools are actually
実は天文学学校は、
Like most scientists
ほとんどの科学者と同じように
This signal is actually
実はこの信号は、
the more the merrier
多いほどもっと良いでしょう
So it's better if I can
だからできれば良いのですが
collect all
すべて集める
from the universe
宇宙から
able to reach the earth
地球に到達できる
collect it all at once
一度に全部集める
what does it mean to collect well
よく集めるとはどういう意味ですか
It doesn't matter which direction you come from
どちらの方向から来たかは関係ありません
i can tell
私が言うことができる
when did you come to my earth
あなたはいつ私の地球に来ましたか
Then you come here and there are a few trees
それからここに来ると、数本の木があります
Then I also know the energy of each photon
そうすれば、各光子のエネルギーもわかります
That is to say, I hope
つまり、願っています
I can do things that say
と言う事が出来るんです
I have high resolution
高解像度を持っています
spatial resolution
空間解像度
time resolution
時間分解能
Then I can measure the light very accurately
そうすれば光を非常に正確に測定できるようになります
And then there's also very high-resolution spectra at the same time
同時に非常に高解像度のスペクトルも得られます
just know
今知りました
Hey, this light is red
ねえ、この信号は赤いよ
this light is blue
この光は青いです
at different points in time
さまざまな時点で
Each of these different colors of light
それぞれの異なる光の色
how to hit earth
地球にぶつかる方法
like this image
この画像のように
This is a
これは
First you make the image of Xingyun Neng 31
まず、Xingyun Neng 31 の画像を作成します
So of course astronomers want to say
もちろん天文学者はこう言いたいのです
I just need to take a picture
写真を撮ればいいだけです
I'm not only able to know the inside of this
内部を知ることができるだけでなく、
how bright everything is
すべてがどれほど明るいか
I can still know
まだ知っていますか？
that goes with the matter
それは問題です
what kind of change
どのような変化ですか
And what kind of this is in it
で、これはどんなのが入ってるのかな
gas or metal
ガスか金属か
or various elements like this
またはこのようなさまざまな要素
Of course, to achieve this is actually
もちろん、これを達成するには実際には
It's very, very difficult to be honest
正直に言うのはとてもとても難しい
Because we know the range of electromagnetic waves
電磁波の範囲はわかっているので
is very very big
とてもとても大きいです
is that it can be read from the radio
それはラジオから読めるということです
all the way to infrared all the way to our visible light
赤外線に至るまで、可視光に至るまで
then to UV
それから紫外線へ
Then to X-ray or even this GaMaRay with shorter wavelength
次に、X線、またはさらに短い波長のこのGaMaRayに移行します。
Those electromagnetic waves of different wavelengths
それらの波長の異なる電磁波は、
It brings us a different message
それは私たちに異なるメッセージをもたらします
That also means that it is correspondingly
ということもそれに準じてということですね
Emitted by this celestial body with different temperatures
温度の異なるこの天体から放射される
What about the different electromagnetic waves?
電磁波の違いはどうなるのでしょうか？
Because of its different characteristics
それぞれ異なる特性があるため、
So when you are going to collect these signals
したがって、これらの信号を収集するときは、
you have to use a different method
別の方法を使用する必要があります
So although it is still ideal
なので、まだ理想的ではありますが、
I want to say that if I have an ideal this
理想があるならこう言いたい
I know this astronomical instrument once
この天文器具は一度は知っています
Hey, what is this calling in?
おい、これは何を呼んでいるの？
Gamma Ray or X-Ray or
ガンマ線とかX線とか
Visible light or microwave signal
可視光またはマイクロ波信号
But actually this is
でも実はこれは
So far we have not been able to do this
これまでのところ私たちはこれを行うことができませんでした
So usually when we develop astronomical instruments,
ですから通常、私たちが天文機器を開発するときは、
We'll take the band and separate it
バンドを取り出して切り離してみます
For example, I mostly do
たとえば、私が主にやっているのは、
this band
このバンド
Visible light and infrared
可視光線と赤外線
Then some people will do this high-energy
そうしたら、何人かの人々がこの高エネルギーを行うでしょう
This detection of S light or Gamma Ray
S光またはガンマ線の検出
that astronomical instrument it of course
その天文器具はもちろん
After getting these data
これらのデータを取得した後、
it's basically doing analysis
基本的には分析を行っています
I was just talking about different colors of light
私はちょうどさまざまな色の光について話していました
It represents different substances
さまざまな物質を表します
or different physical properties
または異なる物理的特性
Different substances may be
異なる物質が存在する可能性があります
if i go and say
私が行って言ったら
A celestial body emits this spectrum
天体はこのスペクトルを放射します
There are some absorption lines in the spectrum
スペクトルにはいくつかの吸収線があります
Then this absorption line is usually
すると、この吸収線は通常、
It means that in my mind and body
それは私の心と体に
or inside this cloud
あるいはこの雲の中
are specific to these molecules
これらの分子に特有のものです
Those molecules can make me
それらの分子が私を作ることができる
can absorb this
これを吸収できる
This light that continuously emerges above
上に浮かび続けるこの光
But continuous emergence also makes sense
しかし、継続的な出現にも意味がある
The continuous emergence usually has this intensity distribution of its
継続的な出現は通常この強度分布です
tell us yes
そうだと言ってください
The temperature of this celestial body
この天体の温度は
what about besides this
これ以外にはどうですか
of course i want
もちろん欲しいです
I have another method which is
私には別の方法があります
I can go and get this whole full image
この全体像を取りに行くことができます
or smooth
または滑らかな
The image can get the relative position
画像の相対位置を取得できる
every celestial body
あらゆる天体
Relatively warm position between
間の比較的暖かい位置
then its brightness
それからその明るさ
Then follow its distribution
次に、その配布を追跡します
Then these can sometimes tell us that
そして、これらは時々私たちに次のことを教えてくれるでしょう
do they belong to the same area
彼らは同じ地域に属していますか
celestial body
天体
Is there some between them
彼らの間に何かありますか
The role of interaction
インタラクションの役割
That light will show us the different substances
その光は私たちにさまざまな物質を見せてくれるでしょう
its
これは
scalar size
スカラーサイズ
or temperature
または温度
it even you can know it
それはあなたでも知ることができます
distance from our telescope
私たちの望遠鏡からの距離
Because different celestial bodies will have different displacements
天体が異なれば変位も異なるため
Because of the Doppler effect
ドップラー効果のせいで
So from the spectrum we can see its distance
スペクトルからその距離がわかります
Another possibility is that the light that can be excited by it
もう一つの可能​​性は、それによって励起される光です。
the direction of its intensification can understand its various environments
その激化の方向は、それが置かれているさまざまな環境を理解することができます
And is there any magnetic field distribution near it?
そしてその近くに磁場分布はあるのでしょうか？
Then this is NASA and there is a famous picture
それから、これはNASAで、有名な写真があります
It puts all of NASA's intensification
NASA のすべての強化が込められています
This view of the entire Milky Way
この天の川全体の眺め
Images at different wavelengths draw it
異なる波長の画像が描く
that can see the Milky Way from high energies all the way down to very low energies
高エネルギーから非常に低エネルギーまで天の川を見ることができます。
it actually looks different
実際は違って見える
That's why it's different, of course
だから違うんだよ、もちろん
Including whether there is something in it that it will absorb
吸収するものが入っているかどうかも含めて
For example, in visible light, it has a lot of dust
例えば可視光ではゴミが多い
will absorb
吸収します
The signal is at a relatively high-energy position
信号は比較的エネルギーの高い位置にあります
In fact, it can really emit this high-energy
実際、この高エネルギーを放出することができます。
The source of the signal
信号源
Relatively speaking, it is much less than visible light or infrared light.
相対的に言えば、可視光線や赤外線よりもはるかに小さいです。
So scientists have to compare the different wavelengths
したがって、科学者は異なる波長を比較する必要があります
Detect this info for us
この情報を検出してください
I just managed to piece together the whole thing.
なんとか全体をつなぎ合わせることができました。
celestial man, this image of celestial
天人、この天体のイメージ
or to fully know
または完全に知ること
what happened to it in these places
こんなところで何が起こったのか
So what we just said, astronomers need to know
つまり、私たちが今言ったこと、天文学者は知っておく必要があります
complete this entire electromagnetic wave this
この電磁波全体を完成させてください
range of this message
このメッセージの範囲
But it's a pity we live on the earth
しかし、私たちが地球に住んでいるのは残念です
What about this earth?
この地球はどうなるのでしょうか？
One thing that is very important to us is the atmosphere
私たちにとって非常に重要なことの一つは雰囲気です
As for the atmosphere, it is very important to human beings
空気というのは人間にとってとても大切なものです
We have to breathe every day, we need oxygen
私たちは毎日呼吸しなければなりません、酸素が必要です
In fact, he is...
実は彼は...
What about humans?
人間はどうでしょうか？
Of course, it also blocks a lot of things that are harmful to humans.
もちろん、人体に有害な物質も多くブロックします。
This very high energy electromagnetic wave
この非常に高エネルギーの電磁波は、
Of course, for astronomical observations
天体観測にはもちろん、
Does it block a lot
かなりブロックされますか
The signal that recently came from the universe to the ground
最近宇宙から地上に届いた信号
So generally speaking, observations on the ground
一般的に言えば、地上での観察は
we only have three bands
バンドは3つしかない
That's visible light, infrared, and radio.
それが可視光線、赤外線、電波です。
The signal of these three bands
この 3 つのバンドの信号
We can make astronomical observations from the ground
地上から天体観測ができる
the lower part
下部
Like most of this
これのほとんどのように
X-ray or Gamma Ray
X線またはガンマ線
or longer-wavelength infrared rays
またはそれより長波長の赤外線
We have to launch Sputnik
スプートニクを打ち上げなければなりません
in order to see the impact
効果を見るために
there is no way on the ground
地上には道がない
Besides this effect
この効果以外にも
The atmosphere and the so-called atmospheric labor
大気といわゆる大気労働
what is that atmospheric labor
その大気労働とは何ですか？
Atmospheric labor is
大気労働は、
For example, when the weather is hot
例えば、暑いとき
If you see no oil on the road
道路上にオイルがない場合
There are often things like distorted images that appear
歪んだ画像が表示されることがよくあります
Then this is because of your atmosphere on the surface
それなら、これは表面上のあなたの雰囲気のせいです
its own uneven temperature
独自の温度ムラ
If the temperature is uneven
温度が均一でない場合
Its refractive index will be different
屈折率が違うんだろうね
the light will be biased
光が偏ってしまう
Then the light is biased
すると光が偏ります
Usually when we look at the stars
通常、私たちが星を見るとき、
that's what we used to sing when we were kids
それは私たちが子供の頃よく歌っていたものです
twinkle Twinkle Little Star
キラキラ光る
That day is a little star
あの日は小さな星
that sparkle
その輝き
In fact, it is the astroman who hates the most
実は一番嫌いなのは天文学者です
That twinkle twinkle sparkle sounds so
きらきらきらめきがそう聞こえる
seems very romantic
とてもロマンチックに思えます
Actually it's very, very bad for Astroman
実際、それはアストロマンにとって非常に悪いものです
because it
なぜならそれは
If you put this twinkle twinkle star
このきらきら星を入れたら
high speed video
ハイスピードビデオ
It looks like this when you look at it
見てみるとこんな感じ
The star is actually running around all the time
星は実際にいつも走り回っている
Then its point of light is not a
その場合、その光の点は
Not a fully focused spot of light
完全に焦点が合った光点ではない
So this creates this point of light on this star
それで、これはこの星にこの光点を作ります
will be big
大きくなるでしょう
will be much larger than the optical quality we originally designed
当初設計した光学品質よりもはるかに大きくなります
Then this deflection has the greatest effect on electromagnetic waves with shorter wavelengths
この偏向は、より短い波長の電磁波に最も大きな影響を及ぼします。
So on the ground because we can only see the shortest visible light
地上では最短の可視光しか見えないので
It's probably a little bit visible in ultraviolet light.
紫外線で少し見えるかも知れません。
So visible light has the greatest effect
つまり可視光が最も大きな影響を与えるのです
If it is electromagnetic waves like me, this is the image of a black hole
私のような電磁波ならブラックホールのイメージです
An electric shuttle with such a long wavelength cannot see this
波長が長い電気シャトルではこれを見ることはできません
So we can see images of black holes from the ground
ブラックホールの画像を地上から見ることができる
Also because it doesn't have this
これも無いので
You can get such a high-resolution video
こんな高画質な動画が手に入るんですね
It is also because it does not have the relationship of atmospheric labor
大気労働の関係がないからでもある
The different wavelength ranges actually look very different
異なる波長範囲は実際には非常に異なって見えます
this is
これは
This is the visible light instrument that you are more likely to be more familiar with.
これは誰もがよく知っている可視光計測器です。
a camera
一個相機
But the camera is really big
しかしカメラは本当に大きいです
it is about three meters high
高さは約3メートルです
people are there
人がそこにいる
Then there is a big mirror
それから大きな鏡があります
lens
レンズ
Then I take my
それから私は私のものを取ります
this film
このフィルム
It's like my detector is here
まるで探知機がここにあるみたいだ
that looks weird
それは奇妙に見える
I don't know what it is
それが何なのか分かりません
This is
これは
Gamma Ray is high energy
ガンマ線は高エネルギーです
This telescope of electromagnetic waves
この電磁波望遠鏡
then why make it like this
ではなぜこのようにするのか
He hopes that when these electromagnetic waves come
彼は、これらの電磁波が来たら、
he used very
彼はとても使いました
very low angle
非常に低い角度
call me this
これに電話してください
scattered leaves
散らばった葉
Then
それから
let him do this
彼にこれをやらせてください
This scattering at very low angles
この散乱は非常に低い角度で発生します
Because usually this high-energy electromagnetic wave can easily penetrate
通常、この高エネルギーの電磁波は容易に透過するため、
like we shine light
私たちが光を照らすように
When the same time, the S light is direct
同時にSライトが直進すると
penetrate our body and hit the back
体を貫いて背中を叩く
so you only have very high angles
つまり、非常に高い角度しかありません
This angle of incidence at very low angles
非常に低い角度でのこの入射角
You want to collect his pick number
彼の指名番号を集めたい
so he has a
それで彼は
so weird
とても奇妙
This is our GOT receiver for observing black holes
ブラックホール観測用のGOT受信機です。
Because it is an electromagnetic wave, a microwave with a very long wave field
電磁波なので、非常に長い波動を持つマイクロ波です。
So when it arrives, there will usually be a Fee Home in front of it
そのため、到着すると、通常、その前にフィーホームがあります
It's kind of like a horn
なんだかホルンみたいですね
There is a natural function that allows electromagnetic waves to converge
電磁波を収束させる自然の働きがある
So usually in microwave receivers
通常、マイクロ波受信機では
You'll see something like
次のようなものが表示されます
just said so much
それだけ言いました
In fact, on every temperature platform
実際、あらゆる温度プラットフォームで
Regardless of which band the weather station
どのバンドの気象観測所であっても
In fact, they all carry a lot of different instruments
実際、彼らは皆、さまざまな楽器を持っています
I will give two different examples here
ここでは 2 つの異なる例を示します
One is that these two are binoculars that cooperate with our Tianwen team.
1 つは、この 2 つは天文チームと協力している双眼鏡であるということです。
one is japan
一つは日本です
I asked Taiwan about this SUVAR binoculars
このSUVAR双眼鏡について台湾に聞いてみた
what about this
これはどうですか
I just listed all the instruments it currently has
現在持っているすべての楽器をリストしました
look wow
すごいね
one two three four five six seven seven
一、二、三、四、五、六、七、七
then it is an eight meter telescope
それなら8メートルの望遠鏡です
then this is the real photo
それからこれが本当の写真です
my real photo
私の本当の写真
It is difficult for you to understand why it can hold so many at once
なぜ一度にこれほど多くのものを保持できるのか理解するのは困難です
that's actually because
それは実際にはだからです
it has several focal points in this telescope
この望遠鏡にはいくつかの焦点があります
several that is to say
いくつか、つまり
i have a primary mirror
私は主鏡を持っています
What about the light in space?
宇宙の光はどうでしょうか？
After reaching my primary mirror
主鏡に到達した後
I can image right where the main focus is
主な焦点がどこにあるのかを正確にイメージできます
I can make a camera right here
ここでカメラを作れます
For example, this wide-angle mirrorable light camera is placed here
たとえば、この広角ミラーラブルライトカメラはここに設置されています
Then I have another imaging method
それから、別のイメージング方法があります
That's when I replaced this camera with a lens and another lens
それは私がこのカメラをレンズと別のレンズに交換したときです
Then my signal will go to my this
そうすれば、私の信号は私のこれに送信されます
we are called
私たちは呼ばれています
cover in green focus , another focus
緑のフォーカスでカバー、別のフォーカス
So it can also put other instruments here
したがって、他の楽器をここに置くこともできます
Usually these two instruments usually have different resolutions
通常、これら 2 つの機器は異なる解像度を持っています
The resolution of the main focus instrument will be better than this
メインフォーカス機器の解像度はこれよりも優れています
In this cover forest focus, the one above is slightly worse
このカバーフォレストフォーカスでは、上のものはわずかに悪いです
In addition, there are two platforms on both sides of it
さらに、その両側に2つのプラットフォームがあります
How to use two flat platforms
2つの平らなプラットフォームの使い方
That is, I put this in the middle of the light input and add another mirror
つまり、これを光入力の真ん中に置き、別のミラーを追加します
we're going to have a third mirror
3番目の鏡を作るつもりです
The third mirror is when my light hits the trail and after my second mirror
3 番目のミラーは、光がトレイルに当たるときと 2 番目のミラーの後であります。
Then hit this third mirror, which can make my light go to both sides
次に、この 3 番目の鏡に当たると、光が両側に行きます。
what is the advantage of going both ways
双方向に行くメリットは何ですか
It is on these two platforms
この 2 つのプラットフォーム上にあります
The instruments on it will not move with the telescope
搭載されている機器は望遠鏡と一緒に動きません
is suitable for very high-resolution observations
非常に高解像度の観察に適しています
So on a binoculars, you can see that there are many
双眼鏡で見ると、たくさんあるのがわかります。
different this instrument
この楽器は違う
If these instruments are carefully analyzed
これらの機器を注意深く分析すると、
i use different color words
私は違う色の言葉を使っています
put some emphasis on it
それにある程度重点を置く
Look, visible light, visible light, visible light
見てください、可視光、可視光、可視光
Infrared ray Golden outer ray Infrared ray Medium yellow outer ray
赤外線 黄金色の外光線 赤外線 中黄色の外光線
Representatives say different instruments
さまざまな楽器を表します
You are usually related to its wavelength
あなたは通常、その波長に関係しています
because of the different wavelengths
波長が違うから
you need to use different
別のものを使用する必要があります
Mainly different detectors
主に異なる検出器
Also its lens is different
レンズも違います
So usually you an instrument
つまり、通常、あなたは楽器です
It will only be suitable for a fixed wavelength range
固定された波長範囲にのみ適しています
It has no way to cover very large range
非常に広い範囲をカバーする方法はありません
This is what we basically
これが私たちが基本的に行っていることです
Limitations of our materials
弊社の材料の限界
Material limitations of my shots
私のショットの物質的な制限
and the material constraints of my detector
そして私の検出器の材料上の制約
In addition, the biggest difference is
さらに、最大の違いは、
many are cameras
多くはカメラです
Some can be cameras and can also be used as spectrum camps
一部はカメラとして使用でき、スペクトルキャンプとしても使用できます
Usually if you want to high-resolution spectrum
通常、高解像度のスペクトルが必要な場合は、
it can only see
それは見ることしかできない
It scatters the light of the celestial body very widely
天体の光を非常に広範囲に散乱させる
let you get more of this
これをもっと手に入れましょう
There is this information about its elements and its speed
その要素と速度については次の情報があります
So what about the spectrometer?
では、分光計はどうでしょうか？
Usually it's different from the camera
通常、カメラとは異なります
It is equal to two different things separated
それは 2 つの異なるものを分離したものに等しい
That's why it can be a camera at the same time
だからこそ、同時にカメラとしても機能します
cannot be spectrum
スペクトルになることはできません
Usually that's when you're doing this revealing design
通常、このような露出度の高いデザインを行うときは
You need to use your brains a little bit
少し頭を使う必要がある
For example, I am a moving thing
たとえば、私は動くものです
After I plug this thing in
これを差し込んだ後
it turns from camera to spectrum
カメラからスペクトルへ変わります
Such a form to achieve this multi-purpose instrument
この多目的な楽器をこんな形で実現
Another example is
別の例は
Another word of our cooperation
私たちの協力のもう一つの言葉
Already called JCNT
すでに JCNT と呼ばれています
it's a radio
それはラジオです
the radio binoculars
ラジオ双眼鏡
it has four different astronomical instruments
4つの異なる天文器具があります
on top of the same binoculars
同じ双眼鏡の上に
it's actually the same
それは実際同じです
it will have a mirror to fold
折りたためるミラーが付いています
When mirrors are folded in different directions
ミラーを異なる方向に折りたたむ場合
my different astronomical instruments
私のさまざまな天文器具
can play its role
その役割を果たすことができる
what does it have on it
それには何が付いていますか
it's the same camera planner
同じカメラプランナーです
I got a weird thing here
ここで奇妙なものを見つけました
extrapolation receiver
外挿受信機
This thing is actually in Chinese, I was also the day before
これは実は中国語で、私も前日に行きました。
while doing this translation
この翻訳をしながら
I just found out that it's called an external receiver.
外部受信機というものだと今知りました。
English is called Hitrodai
英語ではヒトロダイといいます。
Receiver
受信機
it's actually a
それは実際には
Can know the recent
最近のことを知ることができる
this phase of light
この光の段階
A receiver for the phase of electromagnetic waves
電磁波の位相を受信する受信機
it usually has a reference
通常は参照があります
Reference electromagnetic waves come in
基準電磁波が入ってくる
follow me from space
宇宙から私を追いかけてください
this signal from
この信号は
interfere
干渉
Usually you have two signal cell waves with the same wavelength
通常、同じ波長を持つ 2 つの信号セル波があります。
when interfering
干渉するとき
If you know the phase of a battery wave
電池の波の位相がわかれば
you can know another phase
別のフェーズを知ることができます
So they have something like this
それで彼らはこのようなものを持っています
Of course on a cordless phone headset
もちろんコードレス電話機のヘッドセットでも
It also has astronomical instruments like a normal camera
通常のカメラと同様に天文機器も搭載
In this case, it has many wavelengths
この場合、波長がたくさんあります。
Scoobatux is currently the world's most powerful observation
スクーバタックスは現在世界で最も強力な観測結果です
this radio camera
このラジオカメラ
It provides 450 and 850 micron images
450 および 850 ミクロンの画像を提供します
450 microns is just short of our visible light
450ミクロンは可視光線にわずかに届きません
about 1000 times the wavelength
波長の約1000倍
Our eyes see red light at about 0.6 microns
私たちの目は約0.6ミクロンの赤色光を見ます
So this is about 1000 times worse
つまり、これは約1000倍悪いです
so their instruments
だから彼らの楽器は
When designing, it uses the same materials as ordinary visible light
設計時には通常の可視光線と同じ材料を使用
The materials used will be different
使用する素材も異なります
Then there will be a big difference
そうすると大きな違いが出てくるよ
So usually when we do training
ですから、通常、トレーニングをするときは、
For example, I specialize in visible light infrared
例えば、私は可視光赤外線を専門としています。
It's hard for me to have this technology with those radios at the same time
このテクノロジーをこれらの無線機と同時に使用するのは困難です
So in our astronomical institute
それで私たちの天文学研究所では
We basically split into two big groups
私たちは基本的に 2 つの大きなグループに分かれます
One is visible light and infrared light
一つは可視光線と赤外線です
Also do this
これもやってください
Development of everything related to black hole radio
ブラックホール電波に関するあらゆる開発
Well, what is the difference between everything in astronomy and science in general?
では、天文学と科学一般の違いは何でしょうか?
We know there are actually many different research units in the House of Representatives
下院には実際にさまざまな研究部門があることを私たちは知っています
There are many with 31
31が多い
Then 20 of these 31 firms probably
そうすると、これら 31 の研究所のうち 20 はおそらく
In fact, there are many, many instruments in the tree pear group and the life science group.
実際、樹梨グループと生命科学グループには、非常に多くの機器があります。
So what is the difference between these instruments and our astronomical instruments?
それでは、これらの機器と私たちの天文機器との違いは何でしょうか？
Probably these three points
たぶんこの3点
is the first
最初です
There is no way to control what astronomy observes
天文学が何を観察するかを制御する方法はありません
and it's far away
そしてそれは遠いです
So its signal is quite weak when it reaches the earth
したがって、地球に到達するときの信号は非常に弱いです
there are of course few exceptions
もちろん例外はほとんどありません
For example, if I want to look at the sun
例えば太陽を見たいと思ったら
the sun is actually very, very bright
太陽は実際にはとてもとても明るいです
Our usual nighttime instrument
いつもの夜の楽器
Once placed in the sun, it burns immediately
日に当たるとすぐに燃えてしまいます
the whole thing is broken
すべてが壊れています
So in the field of astronomical instruments
天文機器の分野では
Being the sun is actually a very special
太陽であるということは、実はとても特別なことなのです
What they need to consider is also very different from that of ordinary astronomical instruments used at night
夜間に使用する通常の天文観測機器とは考慮すべき点も大きく異なります
But most astronomical instruments still target this very weak signal
しかし、ほとんどの天文機器は依然としてこの非常に弱い信号をターゲットにしています
to do
すること
to make this design
このデザインを作るために
Because this design needs to detect this very small signal
この設計ではこの非常に小さな信号を検出する必要があるため、
So what it needs is a very quiet environment
したがって、必要なのは非常に静かな環境です
that's usually in physics because what we think of as a quiet environment
それは通常、物理学の世界です。なぜなら、私たちは静かな環境を考えるからです。
Just let the temperature of this thing drop down
このものの温度を下げてください
Especially this detector of yours
特にあなたのこの探知機は
So everyone, do you all have cell phones?
さて皆さん、携帯電話は持っていますか？
Mobile phones can take pictures
携帯電話は写真を撮ることができます
Like the videos of Xiuwa when I first started
最初に始めた頃のXiuwaのビデオが好き
it's also very beautiful
それもとても美しいです
These beautiful images have actually been processed.
これらの美しい画像は実際に加工されています。
It didn't look so pretty in the first place
もともとそんなに綺麗じゃなかった
If that is astronomical, we will lower the operating temperature of the camera to
それが天文学的であれば、カメラの動作温度を
at least minus 100 degrees
少なくともマイナス100度
What about when you get to minus 100 degrees?
マイナス100度になったらどうなるでしょうか？
the pictures you took
あなたが撮った写真
to be very clean
とてもきれいになる
But I'll give some examples later
ただし、後でいくつか例を示します
I said it was very clean
とてもきれいだと言いました
But it's actually relative
でもそれは実際には相対的なものです
Actually it looks very ugly
実際に見るととても醜いです
If you haven't dealt with
対処していない場合
but can't stand it
でも我慢できない
Another characteristic of silverware after that day is that
この日以降の銀製品のもう一つの特徴は、
It usually operates around the clock
通常は24時間稼働しています
i put a telescope
望遠鏡を置きました
Tin Hau silverware placed on top of the mountain
山の頂上に置かれた天后の銀器
What about this mountain?
この山はどうでしょうか？
we need to
必要がある
There are observation plans every day
毎日観察プランあり
These observation plans are usually decided half a year ago
これらの観測計画は通常半年前に決定されます
just if i'm going to go ahead with tonight's plan
ただ今夜の計画を進めるつもりなら
Actually scientists
実は科学者
Should have been six months ago or earlier
半年以上前にすべきだった
put forward his observation plan
彼の観察計画を提案する
That came up with some censored work
それは検閲された作品を思いついた
So about three months ago
それで3ヶ月くらい前から
what to observe every day
毎日何を観察するか
This observation plan has been fixed
この観測計画は確定しました
then this i have
それからこれは私が持っています
so here comes the day
それでその日が来ます
if it's my turn i hope this telescope is good
もし私の番なら、この望遠鏡が良いものであることを願っています
this silverware is good
この銀製品は良いです
if it breaks i'm
それが壊れたら私は
I am the opportunity to go public
私は公になる機会です
Then I may have to wait another half a year for this
そうなるとまた半年くらい待たないといけないかも知れません
Opportunity to observe
観察の機会
So our observed
したがって、私たちが観察した
Stability requirements are very, very high
安定性の要件は非常に高い
Which weather station are we usually comparing
私たちは通常どの気象観測所を比較していますか
when it works better
より良く機能するとき
I'm just comparing the light environment
光環境を比較してみると
It will be broken for a few days a year
一年に数日壊れる
That good weather platform may be 365 days a year
その好天プラットフォームは 1 年 365 日あるかも知れません
It's only about 5% broken
5%くらいしか壊れてない
5% of the days
日の 5%
So about 10 days or so
それで10日くらいかな
10 days like this
こんな10日間
that relative to your instrument
あなたの楽器に関連したもの
The instrument must be very stable except for the external environment
機器は外部環境を除いて非常に安定している必要があります
The instrument must be very stable
機器は非常に安定していなければなりません
This way you can satisfy these
そうすればこれらを満たすことができます
Astronomer Observational Needs
天文学者の観測ニーズ
That's another
さらに、それは
this temperature environment
この温度環境
usually just good weather
通常は良い天気です
no cloud place
雲のない場所
So it's a relatively dry environment
比較的乾燥した環境なので、
what about the earth
地球はどうですか
This relatively dry environment
この比較的乾燥した環境
Usually means that the temperature is very low
通常、温度が非常に低いことを意味します
low humidity
低湿度
So what about our instrument
では、私たちの楽器はどうでしょうか
You have to work in a very low environment
非常に低い環境で働かなければならない
So put
ということで
If you put ordinary things in a low-temperature and low-humidity environment,
普通のものを低温低湿の環境に置くと、
sometimes it doesn't work properly
時々正常に動作しないことがある
The most commonly cited example is the
最もよく引用される例は、
Usually the sky culture is already a high mountain
通常、空の文化はすでに高い山です
So a high mountain means that its air pressure is also very low.
つまり、山が高いということは、気圧も非常に低いということになります。
The air is relatively thin
空気が比較的薄い
So in the early days, if you took the hard drive to the mountain
つまり、初期の頃、ハードドライブを山に持っていったとしたら、
That hard drive often fails
そのハードドライブは頻繁に故障します
Because the hard disk is actually very fast to read
ハードディスクは実際には読み取りが非常に速いため、
it spins a fast motor
高速モーターを回転させます
It is because of its fast rotation speed
回転速度が速いからです
Then float up to do this reading action
次に、フロートアップしてこの読み取りアクションを実行します
These drives usually have a high failure rate in the mountains
これらのドライブは通常、山では故障率が高くなります。
Motors because the air is too thin
空気が薄すぎるためモーターが故障
There is no way for others to float it alone
他の人が単独で浮かせる方法はありません
So there are some very special things in this special environment
この特別な環境には非常に特別なものがいくつかあります
some very special factors
いくつかの非常に特殊な要因
When you're developing hot weather
暑くなってきたら
must be taken into account
考慮に入れなければなりません
ok then i'm back with this photo
さて、この写真に戻ります
Then this photo actually tells you that it is inside an instrument
この写真は実際にそれが器具の中にあることを示しています
probably something
おそらく何か
the first one is
最初のものは
We can see that there are of course a lot of screws in here
もちろんここにはたくさんのネジがあることがわかります
We ignore the screw
ネジは無視します
Did you see it has its lens, has its body
レンズとボディがあるのを見ましたか？
And then there's this main electronic part of it
そして、その主要な電子部分があります
And the most important core, the detector inside it
そして最も重要なコア、その中にある検出器
Probably just these few
たぶんこの数人だけ
Form the core of astronomical instruments
天文機器の中核をなす
you have an optical system
光学システムをお持ちですか
You can go get this signal and put it together
この信号を受け取って組み立てることができます
after that you have a detector
その後は探知機が手に入ります
That detector can
その検出器は、
The data that converts your signal from light to electricity
信号を光から電気に変換するデータ
there's some circuitry that handles this electron
この電子を処理する回路がいくつかあります
digitize its signal
その信号をデジタル化する
Then of course you have some mechanical structure
もちろん、何らかの機械的構造があります
make it reachable
到達できるようにする
stable automatic development
安定した自動開発
support your lens
レンズをサポートする
And this detector of yours
そしてあなたのこの探知機は
then i just said
それから私はちょうど言いました
The first is to speak to the news
1つ目はニュースについて話すことです
The most important thing is this astronomical optics system
最も重要なのはこの天体光学系です
that optical system
その光学系
I just saw it mostly from the camera's point of view
ほとんどをカメラの視点から見ました
so you may be
だからあなたもそうかもしれない
that is an imaging system
それは画像処理システムです
That's actually sometimes more than that
実際にはそれを超えることもあります
because if I want to know its spectrum
なぜなら、そのスペクトルを知りたければ
that's in this optical system
それはこの光学系の中にあります
it will have split light
分割光になります
Then sometimes there will be this exciter
それから時々このエキサイターがあります
this other optical system
このもう一つの光学系
Then I can know the light that comes in
そうすれば入ってくる光を知ることができる
What is the direction of its intensification?
その激化はどのような方向に向かうのでしょうか？
The optical system can be said to be in the astronomy department
天文学部とも言える光学系
very important part
非常に重要な部分
because it actually determines the quality of the image
それは実際に画像の品質を決定するためです
field of view size and you can achieve this
視野サイズがあればこれを達成できます
resolution
解析度
The resolution is actually some
解像度は実際にはある程度です
theoretical limit
理論上の限界
I originally brought another small thing to demo today for everyone to see
もともと今日はみんなに見てもらうために別の小さなものをデモに持ってきました
But then it turned out that our laser
しかしその後、私たちのレーザーは
not enough
十分でない
Not powerful enough for everyone to see
誰もが見れるほど強力ではない
but this
しかしこれは
What is the limit of the so-called optical system?
いわゆる光学系の限界はどこまでなのでしょうか？
Basically everyone if
基本的には全員が
When I was in middle school and high school, I did the limit of diffraction
中学、高校の時は回折の極限をやっていました
In fact, this is the limit of the diffraction
実際、これが回折の限界です
Diffraction limit means
回折限界とは
if i had a laser light
レーザー光線があったら
Then there's a small hole here
そしたら、ここに小さな穴があります
What about after the laser light passes through the small hole?
レーザー光が小さな穴を通過した後はどうなるでしょうか?
It will have this circular, this diffracted, this
この円形、これ回折、これ
pattern generated
生成されたパターン
that hole
その穴
smaller
越小
The point of this diffraction is larger
この回折点の方が大きい
what does that mean
どういう意味ですか
My words, if you take this sock as a
私の言葉を、この靴下を例にとると、
your hole
あなたの穴
Then this point represents the one I can image
すると、この点は私がイメージできるものを表します
point size
ポイントサイズ
In this way, it can be estimated that
このようにして推定できるのは、
Where is the limit of this resolution?
この解像度の限界はどこにあるのでしょうか?
So when my sea-goggle gets bigger
だから私の海のゴーグルが大きくなったら
My image quality
私の画質
That is, the limit of its theory will be smaller
つまり理論の限界が小さくなる
that wavelength
その波長
It also depends on the wavelength
波長にもよるけど
If the wavelength is shorter
波長が短ければ
I can also get higher resolution
より高い解像度も得られます
Here I give an example
ここで例を挙げます
everyone has this phone
誰もがこの電話を持っています
In fact, every mobile phone has its lens inside.
実際、すべての携帯電話にはレンズが内蔵されています。
what about the lens
レンズはどうですか
In fact, it will tell you
実際、それはあなたに伝えます
Your lens has a so called this F Ratio
あなたのレンズにはいわゆるこのF比があります
So it is F1.8, F2.0
つまりF1.8、F2.0です
or a digital camera that tells you
またはそれを伝えるデジタルカメラ
How much is this F?
このFはいくらですか？
In fact, this is the D
実はこれがDなんです
in my company
私の会社では
Large D divides this value of small D
大きい D はこの値を小さい D で割ります。
So you put this value in
したがって、この値を入れます
then multiply by your wavelength
それからあなたの波長を掛けます
you can get your limit
あなたはあなたの限界を得ることができます
So if an iPhone 11 latest
つまり、最新のiPhone 11であれば、
What about the iPhone 11 Pro?
iPhone 11 Proはどうですか？
its resolution
その解像度
The theoretical resolution limit is
理論上の解像度限界は次のとおりです。
about a microphone or so
マイクくらい
That's the best that can be achieved theoretically.
それが理論的に達成できる最善のことです。
this resolution
この解像度
Actually because you have some
実はいくつか持っているので、
optical quality above
以上の光学品質
by
に
when assembling
組み立てるとき
Supply differential impact
供差影響
so this
したがって、この
Usually only a theoretical limit
通常は理論上の限界にすぎません
Your real imaging will be much better than this
実際の画像はこれよりもはるかに優れています
Worse
悪い
I just said
私はちょうど言いました
our this
私たちのこれ
atmosphere creates labor
雰囲気が労働を生み出す
Then this atmosphere produces labor
そしてこの雰囲気が労働を生み出す
In fact, it has a great impact on our astronomy.
実際、それは私たちの天文学に大きな影響を与えています。
Basically if you are
基本的にあなたがそうであれば、
when the weather is bad
天気が悪いとき
You can see that this star point keeps shaking
この星の点が揺れ続けるのがわかります
so although
だから、しかし
When we built this big binoculars
この大きな双眼鏡を作ったとき
I theorize it can get very high on this
理論的にはこれで非常に高くなる可能性があります
resolution
解析度
But the atmosphere is here
でも雰囲気はここにある
when moving around
動き回るとき
Actually my resolution
実は私の決意
will be greatly
大きくなるだろう
We just said that Unlimited Power will not be affected by this.
Unlimited Power はこれによる影響を受けないと言いました。
So they came up with a very powerful trick when doing infinite electricity observation.
そこで彼らは、無限電気の観測を行う際に非常に強力なトリックを思いつきました。
is to use special technology to simulate this super large chip
特別な技術を使用してこの超大型チップをシミュレートすることです
What about this huge chip?
この巨大なチップはどうなるのでしょうか？
The so-called ultra-long limit interference shadow
いわゆる超長限界干渉影
That is why we can see black holes this time
だからこそ今度はブラックホールが見えるのです
In fact, it uses this antenna scattered all over the earth
実は地球上に散らばったこのアンテナを使っているのです
Aggregate this signal of his to simulate a very large chip
この信号を集約して非常に大きなチップをシミュレートします
Then I just talked about the limit of this resolution
それから、この解像度の限界について話しました。
It has something to do with the caliber of my chip.
それは私のチップの口径と関係があります。
Therefore, if the aperture of my wafer is small
したがって、ウェハの口径が小さい場合は、
My resolution is poor
解像度が悪いです
Then I am on the ground, I can best simulate the largest situation
そのとき私は地上にいるので、最大の状況を最もよくシミュレートできます
It's me who put this antenna in different corners of the world
このアンテナを世界の隅々に設置したのは私です
Then it will have an antenna the size of an earth
そうすれば地球ほどの大きさのアンテナが付くでしょう
Then we can see our black hole
そうすれば、私たちのブラックホールが見えるでしょう
You see this and the above tells you
これを見れば上記のことがわかります
When the two antennas are very close, the resolution is not good
2 つのアンテナが非常に近い場合、解像度は良好ではありません
when i pull it away
私がそれを引き離すとき
its resolution will increase
解像度が上がります
What about the actual operation inside?
実際の内部動作はどうなっているのでしょうか？
It is more complicated than the concept just now
先ほどの概念よりも複雑です
because I'm actually simulating the entire Earth
実際に地球全体をシミュレートしているからです
When it comes to size, I have several points
サイズに関してはいくつかのポイントがあります
That is, my antenna may have seven or eight points
つまり、私のアンテナには 7 つまたは 8 つのポイントがある可能性があります。
in various places around the globe
世界中のさまざまな場所で
Then I have to rely on the earth's rotation
それなら地球の自転に頼るしかない
To make up for the distance between this point and the point
この点と点の間の距離を補うには
so that my image will become clearer and clearer
私のイメージがより鮮明になるように
Then this is what we were before
それから、これが以前の私たちの姿です
When doing this black hole observation
このブラックホール観測を行う際には
can get this
これを手に入れることができます
Why can you get such a fresh image
なぜこんなにも新鮮なイメージが持てるのか
very important reason
非常に重要な理由
What about visible light?
可視光線についてはどうでしょうか？
is when you have a lot of this old hole
この古い穴がたくさんあるときです
Actually you didn't
実際にはそうではありませんでした
I can't achieve the effect of the interference I mentioned in the image just now
先ほどの画像で述べた干渉の効果が得られません
Because the effect of this interference is actually when the signal comes from outer space
なぜなら、この干渉の影響は実際に信号が宇宙から来た場合に起こるからです。
it has not been disturbed by any
何にも邪魔されていない
So what about this light in a different position?
では、別の位置にあるこのライトはどうでしょうか?
You can combine it to achieve the effect of imaging
組み合わせてイメージング効果を実現できます
What if you have a large disturbance
大きな混乱が起きたらどうするか
My scent information has changed
フレグランス情報が変更されました
At this time, I have no way to achieve the effect of this interference.
現時点では、この干渉の効果を実現する方法はありません。
So in general at the wavelength of visible light
したがって、一般に可視光の波長では
We have this phase difference caused by this atmospheric vibration
この大気の振動によって位相差が生じます。
I have no way to do this intervention
この介入を行う方法はありません
So the interference of the ultra-long line just mentioned
つまり、先ほど述べた超ロングラインの干渉
It's all only possible over the radio.
それはすべて無線でのみ可能です。
in visible light or infrared
可視光または赤外線で
We're going to use some special methods
いくつかの特別な方法を使用します
This has a special term called modulation optics
これには変調光学と呼ばれる特別な用語があります。
What is the meaning of modulation optics
変調光学の意味は何ですか
I want to take this atmospheric old hole out of it
この雰囲気のある古い穴を取り除きたい
Atmospheric old holes usually when light passes through the atmosphere at different altitudes
通常、光がさまざまな高度で大気を通過するときに生じる大気中の古い穴
Originally its light should be the red and green lines represent the wavefront of light
本来その光は光の波面を表す赤と緑の線であるはずです
That is, when the light signal comes in, you pull up the highest point of its vibration position
つまり、光信号が入ると振動位置の最高点を引き上げます。
Logically it should be flat
論理的にはフラットになるはずです
There is this kind of light coming in flat, parallel light coming in
このような光が平面的に入ってきて、平行な光が入ってきます。
When the wavefront is this parallel I can get a perfect image
波面がこれくらい平行だと完璧な画像が得られます
But after passing through the atmosphere, it usually becomes the appearance of the external airflow
しかし、大気圏を通過した後は、通常、外部気流の外観になります。
Then if I want to correct the appearance of the external airflow, I have to use a distorted mirror
外部の空気の流れの外観を修正したい場合は、歪んだミラーを使用する必要があります。
I just let this distorted mirror twist along with this my wavefront
この歪んだ鏡を私の波面と一緒にねじらせただけです
Then twist with the wave front
次に波面に合わせてツイストします
It passes through this mirror reflection, and its peeling will be flat
この鏡面反射を通過すると、剥がれは平らになります
After that mediocre, I'll get
その平凡な後、私は得るでしょう
Same as my interference limit
私の干渉限界と同じ
such a sharp impact
とても鋭い衝撃
that's a video
それはビデオです
This is King Kate glasses
こちらはキングケイトのメガネです
They do this modulation optics
彼らはこの変調光学を行っています
The image turned out to be blurry
画像がぼやけてしまいました
After I turned on the modulation optics correction
変調光学補正をオンにした後
The image suddenly becomes very sharp
画像が突然非常に鮮明になります
That's the difference when you take the atmospheric old hole
まあ、それはあなたが雰囲気のある古い穴を取るときの違いです
after fixing it
それを修正した後
You can get very beautiful images
とても綺麗な画像が得られます
that beautiful image
その美しいイメージ
it has some full size restrictions
フルサイズにはいくつかの制限があります
Because of this atmospheric old hole
この雰囲気のある古い穴のせいで
different in different positions
異なる位置で異なる
we have a noun called
私たちにはという名詞があります
It's your Cohirin's Lens
それはあなたのコヒリンのレンズです
That is to say, how big is the atmosphere?
つまり、大気の大きさはどれくらいですか？
its old hole is the same length
古い穴は同じ長さです
In Taipei City, this range may only be about 20 centimeters
台北市では、この範囲はわずか 20 センチメートル程度である可能性があります
The environment on the mountain is better
山の環境が良くなった
maybe a few meters
おそらく数メートル
so you take this
だからあなたはこれを受け取ります
When the difference caused by the atmospheric flood is completely corrected
大気洪水による差が完全に解消されたとき
In fact it is only in this
実はこれだけです
you can see you can refer to
参照できることがわかります
can measure this
これを測定できます
The vicinity of this point where the old cave looks like
古い洞窟が見えるこの付近
will have a good impact
良い影響を与えるだろう
so you see this
それでこれを見ます
This frame is actually very, very small
このフレームは実際には非常に小さいです
It is only 0.8 x 0.8
たったの0.8×0.8です
arc seconds
アーク秒
One arc second is 3600th of a degree
1 秒角は 3600 度です
so you know it this is actually watching
それで、これは実際に見ていることがわかります
very very small range
非常に非常に狭い範囲
to see this
これを見るために
So usually this
それで通常はこれ
The problem with modulated optics is that the field of view becomes very, very small
変調光学の問題は、視野が非常に小さくなってしまうことです。
So if it wants
それで、それが望むなら
increase it this
これを増やしてください
What about the field of vision?
視野についてはどうでしょうか？
you just
あなたはただ
do some other tricks
他のトリックをやってみよう
Other tricks include just hitting this laser
他のトリックとしては、このレーザーを当てるだけです
I can shoot lasers in all directions from the wrist glasses
手首のメガネから全方向にレーザーを発射できる
The laser itself is like a reference for me
レーザー自体は私にとってリファレンスのようなものです
After the laser hits it, I will look at the point where the laser shines
レーザーが当たったら、レーザーが光るポイントを見に行きます。
You can know when you go up and down from this laser
このレーザーで上昇と下降を知ることができます
After this atmospheric god it's old hole look
この雰囲気の神の後は古い穴の外観です
i can hit several
何個も打てます
I'll know after a few hits
何回か打てば分かるよ
In this area of ​​the mirror that completes me
私を完成させる鏡のこの領域で
All Atmospheric Old Hole areas above
上記のすべての大気中オールド ホール エリア
This correction actually requires a very fast calculation
この補正には実際には非常に高速な計算が必要です。
because basically you need to achieve
基本的に達成する必要があるので、
More than 500 corrections per second
1秒あたり500回以上の修正
So you need to have a lot of sensors
だからたくさんのセンサーが必要になる
and many lasers
そして多くのレーザー
and then go and do it together
そして一緒にやり遂げましょう
This is currently on the Department of Astronomy
これは現在天文学部に所属しています
It is also a very important field of research
非常に重要な研究分野でもあります
Just to correct the disturbance caused by the atmosphere
大気による乱れを修正するためだけに
That's another reason
それは別の理由です
That's why we have NASA that wants to launch this
だからこそNASAがこれを打ち上げようとしているのです
Havoc grid average or even the next generation
Havoc グリッドの平均、さらには次世代
We say that JWST's access to the network
JWST のネットワークへのアクセスを
That is, the labor of the atmosphere actually limits a lot of this
つまり、大気の働きが実際にこの多くを制限しているのです。
We can reach this limit with ground-based observations
地上観測ならこの限界に到達できる
so if you
それで、もしあなたが
I just said that the average size of our largest net on the ground is 10 meters
先ほど言いましたが、地上にある最大の網の平均サイズは 10 メートルです
The Havoc net is actually very small, it is only 2 meters
ハボックネットは実際には非常に小さく、わずか2メートルです
Then why can 2 meters see farther than 10 meters?
では、なぜ2メートルの方が10メートルよりも遠くまで見えるのでしょうか？
This resolution is an atmospheric effect is a big reason
この解像度は雰囲気効果が大きな理由です
Apart from what I just said, that lens is the one
今言ったこととは別に、あのレンズは
What about resolution
解像度はどうですか
Of course, its design also has a lot to do with the size of my field of vision.
もちろん、そのデザインは私の視野の大きさにも大きく関係します。
If my focal length is short
焦点距離が短い場合
Its field of view is larger
その視野はより広いです
If you have played with the camera
カメラで遊んだことがあるなら
should know
知っておくべき
if the shot is short
ショットが短い場合
usually i can see wide
通常は広く見える
Then if I have a long lens
じゃあ長いレンズを持っていたら
I just zoom in well
よくズームインしただけです
i can see far
遠くまで見える
Then of course we're doing astronomical observations.
もちろん天体観測も行っています。
We hope that the bigger the field of vision, the better.
視野は広ければ広いほど良いと考えています。
If the field of vision is larger
視野が広ければ
I will collect this information in a wider range at one time
より広範囲の情報を一度に収集します
but
しかし
When the field of view is bigger
視野が広いと
The larger the range of angles it enters the light
光が入る角度の範囲が広いほど
so you may have very off-center light coming in
そのため、中心からかなりずれた光が入ってくる可能性があります
at this time
現時点では
when you are doing optical design
光学設計をするとき
it will be very very difficult
とてもとても難しいだろう
the other is you
もう一人はあなたです
The last imaged surface
最後にイメージされたサーフェス
is not a flat
アパートではありません
so this is a
これは
the real photo is
本当の写真は
I discovered a lot of this western alien a while ago
私は少し前にこの西洋のエイリアンをたくさん発見しました
Because there's this satellite called the Keppel satellite
ケップル衛星と呼ばれるこの衛星のおかげで
that actually
それは実際に
This is it
これだよ
It intersects the plane is a curved
平面と交差するのは曲線です
Because you want to make an imaging system with a large field of view
広い視野の撮像システムを作りたいため
It is difficult for you to adjust the curvature of the field of view itself back
視野自体の曲率を後ろに調整するのは難しい
so you end up with
それで結局は
You have to do your imaging on a curved plane
曲面上でイメージングを行う必要がある
This technology will be much more difficult
この技術はもっと難しいだろう
This is an example of a visible light camera that we have previously cooperated with Japan
これは以前に日本と協力した可視光カメラの一例です
Usually in this lens inside the lens of the whole system camera
通常、このレンズはシステム全体のカメラのレンズの中にあります。
There are usually many lenses
レンズの数が多いのが普通
Each lens has its own function
それぞれのレンズには独自の機能があります
It is to correct its chromatic aberration
色収差を補正するためです
Possibly a fix so that the view doesn't turn into a curved view
おそらくビューが曲面ビューにならないように修正される可能性があります
That could be the whole image of this
それがこの作品の全体像かもしれない
twist it to make it small
ねじって小さくします
so in one shot
だから一発で
Usually very, very many lenses are used
通常、非常に多くのレンズが使用されます
So this increase in instrument size
したがって、この機器のサイズの増加により、
These lenses are also getting larger in size
このレンズも大型化が進んでいます
You should be able to see it like this
こんな感じで見れるはずです
its 400
その400
Its radius is 41 cm
半径は41cmです
So the whole lens is about 82 cm
つまりレンズ全体は約82cmです
That's probably pretty close
それはおそらくかなり近いです
The limit of what we can do so far
これまで私たちができることの限界
In addition, if this thing is to be used in infrared
また、これを赤外線で使用する場合は、
Its consideration is different
その配慮は違います
Because this in infrared
これは赤外線なので
camera we often need is
私たちがよく必要とするカメラは
cooler observed temperature
観測温度が低い
I'm going to take all these lenses down to cryogenics
これらのレンズをすべて極低温に運ぶつもりです
How cold is this, probably
どれくらい寒いですか、おそらく
around minus 200 degrees
零下200度左右
at minus 200 degrees
マイナス200度で
you are making this lens
このレンズを作っているのはあなたです
When it comes to the design of this mirror frame
このミラーフレームのデザインに関して言えば、
you have to use some special
特別なものを使用する必要があります
Otherwise, we usually say that heat expands and contracts with cold
それ以外の場合、私たちは通常、熱が膨張し、冷たさが収縮すると言います。
My lenses shrink slowly
レンズがゆっくり縮む
Metals expand when heated and contract when cooled.
金属は加熱すると膨張し、冷却すると収縮します。
So how do you go about cooling down
それで、どうやってクールダウンするのですか
You make this lens able to sustain it
このレンズを長持ちさせることができるのはあなたです
originally designed location
当初設計された場所
That requires some special design
それには特別な設計が必要です
Let it be a very uniform when shrinking
収縮時に均一になるようにする
There is always something holding it
常に何かが掴んでいる
keep it in this fixed position
この定位置に保ちます
that in addition
それに加えて
Design on Infrared
赤外線によるデザイン
its lenses are not big
レンズは大きくありません
The composition is also different
構成も違うし
It is usually divided into two blocks
通常は2つのブロックに分かれています
One is to let the light coming back from the outer mirror
1つは外側のミラーから戻ってくる光を通すことです。
First the paint tool becomes a collimated light at a time
まずペイントツールが一度に平行光になります
that on collimated light
それは平行光上で
We usually have some filters
通常、いくつかのフィルターがあります
or block the outside mirror
またはアウトミラーをブロックする
The unwanted infrared rays that come in
入ってくる不要な赤外線
Only after that did the second imaging
その後初めて2回目のイメージングが行われました
so it's in the infrared
だからそれは赤外線の中にある
its lens
そのレンズ
The number of lenses inside is usually quite a lot.
通常、内部にあるレンズの数はかなり多くなります。
except for this camera
このカメラを除いて
I just said that sometimes what we need is to make it a spectroscopic
時々必要なのはそれを分光器にすることだと言いました
This is our participation in another goby project
別のハゼプロジェクトへの参加です
A pattern for the design of an optical system
光学系設計のパターン
Usually in this light goby
通常このライトハゼでは
it is very complicated to run
実行するのは非常に複雑です
In this example it actually has a Xiafeng
この例では、実際には Xiafeng が含まれています。
The light from Xiafeng
霞峰からの光
It will hit my zero mirror first
最初に私のゼロミラーにぶつかります
and then hit my light
そして私のライトを当ててください
And then bounce back after the light
そして光の後に跳ね返る
same same mirror
同じ同じ鏡
Let it hit back to the lens of this camera of mine
私のこのカメラのレンズにぶつけてみましょう
Let this light that has been split
分けられたこの光を
can be imaged on my detector
私の検出器で画像化できます
So its optical path is usually three-dimensional and very complicated
そのため、その光路は通常三次元的で非常に複雑です。
this tossed and tossed
これは投げて投げた
In the end you'll end up with a spectrum like this
最終的にはこのようなスペクトルになります
This is a high-resolution spectrum
これは高解像度のスペクトルです
You can see this presumably from a microphone
おそらくマイクからこれを見ることができます
Up to 2.5 mics the light is all spread out
最大 2.5 マイクまでの光が全体に広がります
Here you will see that I am all this is the one used by our school
ここで、私はすべてこれが私たちの学校で使用されていることがわかります
spectral lines so you'll see it's bright all the way through
スペクトル線なので、全体的に明るいことがわかります
Spectra also come in many different forms
スペクトルにもさまざまな形があります
This is when I only look at one celestial body
一つの天体だけを眺めるときです
Then spread the light as far as possible
次に、光をできるだけ遠くに広げます
This is a high-resolution spectrometer
これは高分解能分光計です
There's another one where I want to see a lot of different celestial objects at once
一度にたくさんの天体を見てみたいということもあります。
Then make all the celestial bodies line up
そしてすべての天体を一列に並べます
Is this fiber optic or
これは光ファイバーですか、それとも
the shorter one
短い方
Safeng's spectrometer
セーフェンの分光計
Then you see this light of every celestial body
そうすれば、あらゆる天体のこの光が見えます
It separates it in a small range
狭い範囲で区切ります
So the resolution of this optical auxiliary is relatively poor.
したがって、この補助光学装置の解像度は比較的劣ります。
But I see many celestial signals at once
でも一度にたくさんの天体の信号が見える
So this topic of different astronomical studies
したがって、さまざまな天文学の研究に関するこのトピックは
You need to need different instruments
別の楽器が必要になる
Let you achieve different goals like this
このようにさまざまな目標を達成しましょう
I just talked about the optical system
先ほど光学系の話をしました
Another very important thing is of course the detector
もう一つの非常に重要なことは、もちろん検出器です。
After I take the light, whether it is imaging or splitting it,
光を受け取った後、結像するか分割するかにかかわらず、
The most important thing is that you have something to convert the signal
最も重要なことは、信号を変換するものがあることです
The detector will of course determine the sensitivity of the instrument
もちろん、検出器は機器の感度を決定します
if my detector is good
私の探知機が良ければ
Then I can detect very weak signals
そうすれば、非常に弱い信号を検出できるようになります
Wait for my temperature to be lower
体温が下がるのを待ちます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
What about the light? The detector we usually use
光はどうでしょうか? 私たちが普段使っている検出器
It is the well-known semiconductor
言わずと知れた半導体です
Well, there are actually many kinds of semiconductors.
さて、半導体には実にたくさんの種類があります。
Well, what we use most often are thin semiconductors.
そうですね、私たちがよく使うのは薄い半導体です。
Then this thin semiconductor is because there are many on the earth
では、この薄い半導体は地球上にたくさんあるので、
Then it fits perfectly and fits within our light-detectable range.
すると、それは完璧にフィットし、私たちの光が検出できる範囲内に収まります。
exactly the same
まったく同じ
So what about this fine-made detector?
では、この精巧に作られた検出器はどうでしょうか?
That's all the use of this camera
このカメラの使い方はこれだけです
or in astronomical instruments
または天文機器で
But if you want to detect this wavelength
しかし、この波長を検出したい場合は、
If it is longer than the thin detection wavelength
薄い検出波長より長い場合
Then you can't use this Silicon
そうするとこのシリコンは使えなくなります
Then this time you have to use other different materials
次に、今度は他の異なる材料を使用する必要があります
Materials have their limits
材料には限界がある
you need to use a different material
別の素材を使用する必要があります
as detectors for different astronomical instruments
さまざまな天文機器の検出器として
that's in the detector
それは探知機の中にある
There is a very important factor is
非常に重要な要素があります
the size of my pixel
私のピクセルのサイズ
Because the size of the pixel actually determines your
実際にはピクセルのサイズが決定するため、
Final instrument resolution
機器の最終解像度
no matter i put my light on
ライトをつけても
How small can it be concentrated
どこまで小さく集中できるか
If I am one pixel this big
もし私が 1 ピクセルの大きさだったら
Then my light is only a little
そうすれば私の光はほんの少しだけ
I still have the whole pixel lit up
まだピクセル全体が点灯しています
So usually when we design
ですから通常、私たちがデザインするときは、
We'll be looking at the pixel size of this detector
この検出器のピクセルサイズを見ていきます。
Make a match between my resolution
私の決意を一致させてください
We usually choose between two and three pixels
通常、2 ～ 3 ピクセルの間で選択します。
to cover a point of light
光の点を覆う
Theoretically, it is possible to obtain the most effective
理論的には、最も効果的な結果を得ることが可能です。
most efficient to
最も効率的なのは
We say sample your spot of light
私たちはあなたの光の点をサンプリングすると言います
a resolution of
の解像度
So you can achieve the best resolution with the fewest pixels
そのため、最小限のピクセルで最高の解像度を実現できます。
the opposite
反対
That is, if you do it this way
つまり、こうすれば
You can achieve the largest field of view with the least number of pixels
最小限のピクセル数で最大の視野を実現できます
without sacrificing your resolution
解像度を犠牲にすることなく
So something like this
それで、このようなもの
this pattern below
この下のパターン
What is shown in the image is a
画像に表示されているのは、
For the light of the stars, you have 30 pixels
星の光には 30 ピクセルあります
to cover it like this
このようにカバーするには
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Well
良い
Because we use these for astronomy
天文学でこれらを使用するため
Binoculars are very large
双眼鏡はとても大きいです
so its this
それでこれです
long focal length
長い焦点距離
When the focal length is very long, the field of view
焦点距離が非常に長い場合、視野は
This range covered
この範囲はカバーされています
Well
良い
with normal mobile phone
通常の携帯電話で
The range that each pixel can cover
各ピクセルがカバーできる範囲
There will be a huge difference
大きな違いが生じるでしょう
So the pixels we choose will be different
したがって、選択するピクセルは異なります
So the pixels of the astronomical visible light camera are about
つまり、天文可視光カメラのピクセルは約
about 10 microns
約10ミクロン
that ordinary mobile phone
その普通の携帯電話
A cell phone is about a micron
携帯電話は約1ミクロン
then you might want to say
それからあなたは言いたいかもしれません
a micron
ミクロン
i just said
私はちょうど言いました
If a good Apple phone
良い Apple 携帯電話なら
Its lens resolution is approximately
レンズの解像度は約
The light spot is about a few microns
光点は数ミクロン程度
So in fact, the P matching of these two
実際、これら 2 つの P マッチングは、
is already very close to what I just said
すでに私が今言ったことに非常に近いです
because you have to think about saying this
これを言うことを考えなければならないから
the lens itself
レンズ自体
It actually still has some errors
実際にはまだいくつかのエラーがあります
so it may image quality
画質が良いかもしれません
It's about two to three microns
２～３ミクロンくらいです
If you use a micron-sized pixel
ミクロンサイズのピクセルを使用する場合
will reach our
私たちのところに届きます
Use two to three pixels to cover the point of light
2 ～ 3 ピクセルを使用して光の点をカバーします。
the size of this decision
この決断の大きさ
then this is us
それならこれが私たちです
Same as the one that was paired with the lens just now
先ほどレンズと組み合わせたものと同じもの
this detector
この探知機
then it this is a
それならこれは
900 million pixel astronomical camera
9億画素天体カメラ
Then this 900 million pixels put it together
それをこの9億画素でまとめたのです
because a pixel is big
画素が大きいので
So it's about the size of your arm
なので腕くらいの大きさです
That's like our normal camera
それは私たちの普通のカメラと同じです
Commercial cameras are very different
市販のカメラは大きく異なります
Commercial cameras we want to say
私たちが言いたい業務用カメラ
The smaller the better with this thing
このことに関しては小さければ小さいほど良い
The smaller the phone camera, the better.
携帯電話のカメラは小さければ小さいほど良いです。
that astronomy is the opposite
天文学はその逆だということ
Tianwen hopes that the bigger the better, the better.
Tianwen 氏は、大きければ大きいほど良いと考えています。
the bigger words
より大きな言葉
The better you can have this resolution
この解像度があればあるほど良い
The camera used for astronomy is usually
天文学に使用されるカメラは通常、
The photosensitive element used in it is also different.
使用されている感光体も異なります。
This astronomy usually we say it uses the structure of CCD
この天文学は通常、CCDの構造を使用していると言われます
It is CCD and its noise is relatively small
CCDなのでノイズも比較的少ない
Then if you want to use our general commercial CMOS Sensor
一般的な市販のCMOSセンサーを使用したい場合
that looks about the same
それはほぼ同じに見えます
You can't tell it's any different from the outside
外から見ても違いが分かりません
Anyway, it's all black.
とにかく真っ黒です。
that black thing
あの黒いもの
The structure inside is not the same will cause it
内部の構造が同じではないため、
has some disadvantages and some advantages
いくつかの欠点といくつかの利点があります
Generally speaking, CDs for astronomy
一般的に言えば、天文学用の CD です。
Its detection rate and sensitivity are very high
検出率と感度が非常に高い
There is very little noise, but it reads very slowly
ノイズはほとんどありませんが、読み取りは非常に遅いです
So when I'm taking pictures, I'm just very, very slow
だから写真を撮るときはとてもとても遅いんです
No way, just like this camera can
まさか、このカメラと同じように
It's almost like making a video, it keeps coming
まるでビデオを作っているような感じで、ずっと続いていきます
keep reading
読み続けます
The one used for general astronomy
一般天文学に使用されるもの
As for this Sensor, you can read a page in about a second.
このセンサーは1ページを約1秒で読むことができます。
So you'll see this image is
この画像を見るとわかりますが、
That's astronomical because often we all have to
多くの場合、私たち全員がそうしなければならないので、これは天文学的な数字です
It's a long exposure, so it doesn't really matter
長時間露光だからあまり関係ない
So for the most part, astronomy is
したがって、ほとんどの場合、天文学は
I love using this CD
このCDを愛用しています
Because of its, relatively speaking, its Performance is better
比較的にパフォーマンスが優れているため、
That
それか
What about this CMOS camera?
このCMOSカメラはどうでしょうか？
its advantage is
その利点は
The speed is fast, it can do very fast orientation, and can also do some special reading
速度が速く、非常に高速な方向調整が可能で、特殊な読み取りも可能です。
In some projects, like the one we did with a trans-Neptunian eye
いくつかのプロジェクトでは、私たちが海王星の視点で行ったプロジェクトのように、
We just use a CMOS camera to do it, hoping to be able to capture the brightness of the star twenty or twenty times per second
CMOS カメラを使用して、星の明るさを 1 秒あたり 20 回撮影できるようにしたいと考えています。
So this is to really choose one of the above differences
したがって、これは実際に上記の違いのいずれかを選択することになります
What about when you do a good job, when an astronomy department does a good job
あなたが良い仕事をしたとき、天文学部が良い仕事をしたときはどうですか？
As far as the whole can play a very high resolution, this is the big one I just showed
全体が非常に高い解像度で再生できる限り、これは先ほど示した大きなものです
This camera with a large CD gain captures images
大きな CD ゲインを備えたこのカメラは画像をキャプチャします
That is, it can be inserted into the face all the time, and you can magnify it hundreds of times.
つまり、常に顔に挿入することができ、何百倍にも拡大することができます。
Not hundreds of times, you can zoom in tens of thousands of times to see very clear celestial images
何百倍ではなく、何万倍でもズームインすると、非常に鮮明な天体画像が表示されます。
In that video, I just said that there are 900 million pixels
そのビデオでは、9 億ピクセルがあると言いました。
That 900 million pixels covers a lot
9 億ピクセルで多くの領域をカバーできる
We can have more astronomical data
もっと多くの天文データが得られる
Let you do this related research
関連する調査をさせてください
that visible light
その目に見える光
Because this Silicon is relatively cheap
このシリコンは比較的安価なので
So we can do relatively cheap
そのため比較的安価に作ることができます
we can spell many
たくさん綴ることができます
like we just said
先ほど言ったように
There are more than 100 pieces of this sensor on the entire glue plane
このセンサーは接着面全体に 100 個以上あります
what about infrared
赤外線はどうですか
It is basically because of the material
基本的には素材によるものです
So relatively speaking, the cost is much more expensive
したがって、相対的に言えば、コストははるかに高くなります
This is a project we participated in before
以前参加したプロジェクトです
we used four slices
4枚のスライスを使いました
One is 4 million pixels
1つは400万画素
A total of 16 million pixels of this infrared finishing
合計1600万画素の赤外線仕上げ
That 16 million pixels seems to say
その1600万画素はそう言っているようです
Hey, my phone is better than his
ねえ、私の携帯電話は彼の携帯電話よりも優れています
Eh, yes, there is nothing wrong with that
えー、はい、それは何も問題ありません
but this one this one
でもこれはこれ
four
四
four add up to
4つの合計は
Well
良い
I remember correctly, it was 60 million Taiwan dollars
確か6000万台湾ドルだったと記憶しています
These are the four
この4つです
It will be so small when put together
まとめるとこんなに小さくなるのね
Then why this is because it
ではなぜそうなるのかというと、
its making is complicated
作りが複雑です
it usually takes a
通常はかかります
there is one
ここに一つ
The detailed circuit for this readout is below
この読み出しの詳細な回路は以下のとおりです。
Then each pixel
次に、各ピクセル
Each pixel, it has a little this
各ピクセルには、これが少しあります
We call Yindian
私たちはインディアンと呼んでいます
Yin this
陰これ
bump
バンプ
Then this Yin bump is in contact with each of these detectors
次に、この 陰のバンプがこれらの各検出器と接触します。
There is another article about this chip of the detector
この検出器チップについては別の記事があります
each pixel above
上の各ピクセル
to connect it
それを接続するために
Then you can put this
それからこれを置くことができます
The signal from the detector
検出器からの信号
Read it out through the circuit of this Srika
このスリカの回路を通して読み上げてください
that's because of this thing
それはこの事のせいだ
Usually need to work under very low temperature
通常は非常に低い温度下で作業する必要があります
like we did see before
以前見たように
The way this thing works is two hundred degrees below zero
この仕組みは零下 200 度です
So there is a lot of this hot account very wrong
したがって、このホットアカウントの多くは非常に間違っています
You don't want it to break in the middle
途中で壊れるのは嫌だよね
So the technology here is quite, quite complicated.
したがって、ここでのテクノロジーは非常に複雑です。
So that's why it's so expensive
だからあんなに高価なんだよ
it's expensive though
高いけど
But in fact, it will show this video after a while
しかし実際には、しばらくするとこのビデオが表示されます
you won't believe this
あなたはこれを信じないでしょう
one is so expensive
1つはとても高価です
Then what I made seems to be not so good
そうすると、私が作ったものはあまり良くないみたいです
Apart from this you have to have a mechanical system
これとは別に機械システムが必要です
Just some shutters
シャッターがいくつかあるだけ
Then the cryogenic system
次に極低温システム
then vacuum
それから掃除機をかける
Because when you want to lower your Sensor to low temperature
センサーを低温に下げたいときのため
If you didn't vacuum
掃除機をかけなかったら
Then the whole system is completely deiced.
その後、システム全体が完全に除氷されます。
so you need to vacuum
だから掃除機をかける必要がある
then low temperature
それから低温
then there are some motors inside
中にはモーターがいくつかあります
If I want to exchange this filter of mine
私のこのフィルターを交換したいなら
then i need a motor
それからモーターが必要です
and then some are mechanical arms
そしていくつかは機械式アームです
Then the shutter looks like this
するとシャッターはこんな感じになります
The appearance of these things is actually very important
こういったものの見た目は実はとても重要なのです
Because these things have the speed at which they work
なぜなら、これらのことはその動作速度があるからです。
will affect the speed of your observations
観察の速度に影響します
that its accuracy
その精度が
will also affect the one you observe
あなたが観察するものにも影響を与えます
overall accuracy
全体的な精度
then this is
それならこれは
One of the first infrared cameras we worked on
私たちが最初に開発した赤外線カメラの 1 つ
it looks like this
このように見えます
there
そこには
That's the big vacuum gun and the cryogenic system
それは大きな真空銃と極低温システムです
over here is my cooler
ここが私のクーラーです
That cooler is connected to this one
あのクーラーはこれに接続されています
just open the middle
真ん中だけ開けて
After opening this
これを開いてから
Then there is green
それから緑があります
its filter
そのフィルター
that big filter ring
あの大きなフィルターリング
can be rotated here
ここで回転できます
to rotate
回転する
just go to when you need a different color
別の色が必要なときに行ってください
just turn
ただ回してください
turn that filter ring
フィルターリングを回してください
I just forgot to mention that
それを言い忘れていただけです
astronomical this
天文学的なこれ
image has a
画像には
normal camera
通常のカメラ
big difference
大きな違い
It's me, in fact, every time I shoot it, it's black and white
それは私です、実際、撮影するたびに白黒になります
That is, when everyone takes pictures, they will be colored as soon as they are taken.
つまり、みんなが写真を撮ると、撮った瞬間に色がついてしまうのです。
Then why are you shooting in color?
ではなぜカラーで撮影するのでしょうか？
Because we shot in black and white
白黒で撮ったので
That's because in your
それはあなたの中で
There is this green light film in front of the Sensor of the camera
カメラのセンサーの前にこの緑色のライトフィルムがあります
Color green film is usually four pixels inside
カラーグリーンフィルムは通常内側に 4 ピクセルあります
two are green and one is blue and one is red
2 つは緑、1 つは青、1 つは赤です
Four pixels produce a
4 つのピクセルが生成する
this image in color
この画像はカラーで
We don't usually do that in astronomy we just take a photo
天文学では通常そんなことはせず、ただ写真を撮るだけです
We put different color filters in front of this real series
この実際のシリーズの前にさまざまなカラーフィルターを置きます
So I take an image of it could be a green image and then a blue image
それで、私はそれが緑色の画像であり、次に青色の画像になる可能性がある画像を撮ります
Then there is the red image, then I will combine these three images together
次に赤い画像があり、これら 3 つの画像を組み合わせます
It becomes a colored image like this
こんな感じのカラー画像になります
Then why do you do this like this?
では、なぜこのようなことをするのでしょうか？
If I use the general practice of this Sensor
このセンサーの一般的な方法を使用すると、
I have two greens and one red and one blue and when I put it together I actually have some information
緑が 2 つ、赤が 1 つ、青が 1 つあり、それを組み合わせると実際にいくつかの情報が得られます
It was private at the meeting because I was equal to two blues with one in the middle
私はブルー2つと真ん中に1つあったので、会議では非公開でした
There is also a blank space between the two reds
2つの赤の中間にも空白があります
Such a resolution will be problematic for real scientific research
このような解決策は、実際の科学研究にとっては問題となるでしょう
So astronomy is usually achieved by exchanging filters
したがって、天文学は通常、フィルターを交換することによって達成されます
The filter exchange system just talked about the rotating disk
フィルター交換システムは回転ディスクについて説明しました
This is another form we made, like a robot
これは私たちが作ったロボットのような別の形です
What about this robot?
このロボットはどうでしょうか？
He works differently
彼は違う働き方をする
This is a place where we put this whole thing
ここはすべてを置く場所です
Fast forward eight times
快轉八倍速
Let's see how he does it. Basically we put
彼がどのようにそれを行うかを見てみましょう。
our filters
私たちのフィルター
put this
これを置きます
I made the inside of the filter holder
フィルターホルダーの内側を作りました
there are three in there
そこに3つあります
There are three on each side and there's one in here
両側に 3 つあり、ここにも 1 つあります
Mechanical arm
メカニカルアーム
The robotic arm can
ロボットアームは、
put in my
私の中に入れて
in front of the detector
探知機の前で
filter take it away
フィルターを外してください
after taking it away
それを奪った後
There will be a raw sauce station and another raw sauce station
生ソースステーションともう一つの生ソースステーションがあります
Then this raw sauce station can be used to choose different filters
この生ソースステーションを使用してさまざまなフィルターを選択できます
That mechanical arm in the back
後ろの機械のアーム
Push my filter in again
フィルターをもう一度押し込みます
Okay, let's do this filter swap
さて、フィルター交換をしましょう
that thing
その事
In fact, it is no different from ordinary mechanical arms.
実際、それは通常の機械アームと何ら変わりません。
but it's very demanding
しかし、それは非常に要求が厳しいです
the first is
一つ目は
Every time I put the filter back on
フィルターを元に戻すたびに
The repeatability of the position should be very good
位置の再現性は非常に良好である必要があります
So our
それで私たちの
every time you put it back
元に戻すたびに
Its error is 10 microns
その誤差は10ミクロン
10 microns is
10ミクロンは
Of course 1/1 of your hair
もちろん髪の毛の1/1
So I can be positioned very accurately
非常に正確に位置を測ることができるので、
Because the positioning is accurate
位置決めが正確なので
so my image
だから私のイメージ
When I want to stack images of three colors together
3色の画像を重ねたいとき
so that there will be no error
間違いがないように
So it involves a lot of mechanical design
そのため、多くの機械設計が必要になります
how do you get this robot to work
このロボットをどうやって動かすのですか
can be very stable
非常に安定することができます
and then you can put those filters in the same place each time
そうすれば、それらのフィルターを毎回同じ場所に置くことができます
That's another
さらに、それは
I want this thing to be very stable
これを非常に安定させたい
So I remember our requirement at that time was
当時の私たちの要求は次のようなものであったと覚えています
i want this thing
これが欲しいです
RUN a thousand times will not break
千回走っても壊れない
So when we started, we actually
それで、私たちが始めたとき、実際には
It took a lot of effort to make this system stable
このシステムを安定させるには多大な努力が必要でした
raise it all the way up to be able to
できるようになるまで上げてください
It's been running all the time without any problems
ずっと問題なく動いてます
Besides these three things, of course
もちろんこの3つ以外にも、
The most important thing is the so-called electronic system
最も重要なのはいわゆる電子システムです
To make it generate this
これを生成させるには
real need signal
本当に必要な信号
It's these real devices it needs some signal
これらの実際のデバイスには信号が必要です
to make it work
それを機能させるために
Then you also need these signals
次に、これらの信号も必要です
These materials from the real department
実際の部門からのこれらの資料
digitize it
それをデジタル化する
Then generate the image you want
次に、必要な画像を生成します
What about after the image is produced?
画像が生成された後はどうなりますか?
That still needs a lot of this software system
それにはまだ多くのソフトウェア システムが必要です
to make this system
このシステムを作るために
and data processing
そしてデータ処理
Then I just said that we have
それから私はただ言いました、私たちは持っています
make a big this
これを大きくする
Before this stitching
この縫い方の前に
In fact, if you go to see the original filming of it
実際、そのままの形で撮影されているのを見に行くと、
Like actually it's really miserable
実際には本当に悲惨なことのようです
You see this has a lot of things you don't want
これには望まないものがたくさんあることがわかります
For example, white dots, black dots
たとえば、白い点、黒い点など
Then everything seems to be uneven
そうなるとすべてが不均一に見える
Logically speaking, if it is a perfect image
論理的に言えば完璧なイメージであれば
When you take a picture, this should be all the same brightness
写真を撮るとき、これはすべて同じ明るさになるはずです
Because this is the one I use to correct my brightness
これは明るさを補正するために使用するものなので、
an image of
のイメージ
It's a pity that there is usually always a
通常は常にあるのが残念です
some without some
一部なし
For example, bad pixels or your failure
たとえば、ピクセル不良や失敗などです。
The production process fails, for example
生産プロセスが失敗するなど、
in this place you will see
この場所であなたは見るでしょう
there is one
ここに一つ
An Output of this Sensor is missing
このセンサーの出力がありません
So it's all black
だから全部真っ黒だよ
That's visible light
それは可視光です
The safflower line is even worse
ベニバナの系統はさらにひどい
I just talked about the $20,200,000
先ほど2020万ドルの話をしました
The sound and color of these four direction lines
四方向の線の音と色
after it's put together
組み立てた後
you shoot the sky
あなたは空を撃つ
This is what it shows you
これがあなたに示しているものです
Do you have
ありますか
Eh, there is only one horizontal tone
えー、横トーンが1つしかないんです
Then there are things like flowers
それから花のようなものもあります
Then we have to find some way to deal with it
それならそれに対処する何らかの方法を見つけなければなりません
Of course I will be the first to know where this horizontal tune comes from.
もちろん、この水平旋律がどこから来たのかを知るのは私が初めてです。
Hengtune is actually
実はHengtuneは
it's in this
この中にあります
what we call big people
私たちが偉人と呼ぶもの
when there is no exposure
露出がないとき
because you have a hot relationship with itself
あなたはそれ自体と熱い関係を持っているから
have a hot and active relationship
熱く活発な関係を築く
So it already has a little signal
つまり、すでに小さな信号があります
then this should be deducted
それならこれは差し引かれるはずだ
In addition, that means that each Sensor
さらに、それは各センサーが
It has several different outputs
いくつかの異なる出力があります
Then the endpoint of this output
次に、この出力のエンドポイント
The magnification of its magnification is not the same
その倍率の倍率は同じではありません
So this horizontal dialect
つまりこの水平方言は
Mainly because the magnification ratio is not the same
倍率が違うのが主な理由
what about the other
もう一方はどうですか
It's on every Pixel
すべてのピクセルにあります
Sometimes because of its Coding relationship
場合によってはコーディング関係が原因で
Its detection efficiency is not the same
検出効率は同じではありません
So there will be some very strange patterns
非常に奇妙なパターンがいくつかあるでしょう
We can all find a way to get rid of this Penet
私たちは皆、このペネトを取り除く方法を見つけることができます
Then remove the bad points
あとは悪い点を取り除く
Especially this side and here are all bad
特にこっちもここもダメダメ
then remove it like this
それからこのように削除します
Then you can get the corrected image
その後、修正された画像を取得できます
Then the corrected image is not the final one yet.
そうすると、修正された画像はまだ最終的な画像ではありません。
Because in the infrared this sky background
この空の背景は赤外線だから
it has been changing over time
それは時間とともに変化してきた
so you're going to get another no
それでまたノーをもらうことになる
This background without celestial bodies
天体のないこの背景
Finally you can actually get one of these
ついにこれらのいずれかを実際に入手できるようになります
finally finished
最後完成
then you will see this inside this
そうすれば、この中にこれが表示されます
We say we are very lucky
私たちはとても幸運だと言います
will show up clearly
はっきりと現れるでしょう
So this image processing in astronomy is
天文学におけるこの画像処理は
very very important
非常非常重要
Without image processing
画像処理なし
You'll never see such a beautiful image
こんなに美しい映像は二度と見られないでしょう
Actually it is
実はそうなんです
It turned out to be super scary
超怖いことが判明しました
no way
とんでもない
you can't believe this
これは信じられないでしょう
Of course, the black hole just mentioned is also
もちろん、先ほどのブラックホールも
I think if you guys have listened to our previous speeches or press conferences,
私たちのこれまでのスピーチや記者会見を聞いたことがあるなら、
We only need to do this ultra-long limit interference and data processing
この超長時間の制限干渉とデータ処理だけを行う必要があります。
There are four teams in different parts of the world
世界のさまざまな地域に 4 つのチームがあります
Then it took a year to process
それから処理に1年かかりました
That's all data processing
データ処理はこれだけです
actually very very important
実はとてもとても重要
What you just said is usually on the ground.
あなたが今言ったことは、通常は現場で行われます。
What problems will we encounter when developing on the ground
地上で開発する際にどのような問題に遭遇するか
Finally, take a moment to talk about this space abandoned development
最後に、この宇宙放棄された開発について少しお話しましょう
That is different from the ground, in fact, it means
それは地面とは違うということ、実は、
My abandonment has to be able to withstand the launch process
私の放棄は起動プロセスに耐えることができなければなりません
There is usually a lot of vibration during the launch.
通常、発射時には大きな振動が発生します。
and then a lot of this noise
そして、このノイズがたくさん発生しました
Of course it can still operate in the space environment
もちろん宇宙環境でも動作可能
that besides this
これ以外に
Say goodbye to me when you fly up
あなたが飛び立つとき、私にさよならを言ってください
Then if I fly up and break
それで飛び上がって壊れたら
I really have no way
本当に仕方がありません
Like Harvard, it is possible to send space theory to repair it. The probability is
ハーバード大学のように、宇宙理論を送って修復することは可能です。確率は次のとおりです。
Only about two times
たった2回くらい
Now there is no space to say that you can fly to this space.
今、この空間に飛べると言える空間はありません。
So he has high requirements in his heart
だから彼は心の中で高い要求を持っている
So mostly he uses proven techniques
そのため、主に彼は実証済みのテクニックを使用します
That is, no one will use unverified
つまり、未検証のものは誰も使用しません
so we say
だから私たちは言います
we usually joke
私たちはいつも冗談を言います
In fact, all the satellites use technologies ten years ago.
実際、すべての衛星は 10 年前のテクノロジーを使用しています。
Because you want the technology from ten years ago
10年前の技術が欲しいから
then mature
その後成熟する
Then after a long time to do verification
それから、久しぶりに検証してみます
Because space one has a lot of extra testing
スペースワンには追加のテストがたくさんあるので
You're going to do a radiation test
放射線検査をすることになります
There is a lot of radiation in space
宇宙には大量の放射線が存在する
This evidence test
この証拠試験は
You have to be able to work in the space environment
宇宙環境で作業できなければなりません
The space environment is very special, that is, your satellite is usually rotating
宇宙環境は非常に特殊です。つまり、衛星は通常回転しています。
Where the sun shines is hot
太陽が当たるところは暑い
it's cold when turned to the back
後ろを向くと寒いです
so they need to do some
だから彼らは何かをする必要がある
Fractuation at a very special temperature
非常に特殊な温度での破壊
What I just talked about is vibration and noise.
今お話ししたのは振動と騒音です。
The radiation dose in space
宇宙空間の放射線量
Usually it is 100KR
通常は100KRです
that's a
それは
Anyway, this is a unit of radiation dose.
とにかく、これは放射線量の単位です。
that's usually in astronomy
それは通常天文学の世界です
Sometimes you have very special situations
時々非常に特殊な状況に陥ることがあります
That is, you are going to launch this satellite to a farther place
つまり、この衛星をもっと遠くへ打ち上げようとしているのです。
For example, the harshest place is Jupiter
たとえば、最も過酷な場所は木星です
So everything has to be tested first
したがって、最初にすべてをテストする必要があります
that's our detector
それが私たちの探知機です
I don't know if you can see clearly
はっきり見えるか分かりませんが
Are these two different?
この二つは違うのでしょうか？
No
いいえ
Sorry about the resolution problem
解像度の問題については申し訳ありません
In fact, it is our device to fight
実際、それは私たちが戦うための装置です
This radiation dose after doing this test on the ground
地上でこのテストを行った後のこの放射線量
it will have a lot of white spots
白い斑点がたくさんできてしまいます
But here, sorry to see it out
でも、ここで、見ちゃってごめんなさい
Then Jupiter, if you go to Jupiter, play Jupiter is the earth
それからジュピター、もしあなたがジュピターに行ったら、ジュピターは地球だと演奏してください
all this
このすべて
The magnetic field inside the form is the largest
フォーム内の磁場は最大です
The magnetic field is the largest, and its magnetic field lines
磁場が最も大きく、その磁力線は
will capture more of this generation of electric particles
この世代の電気粒子をより多く捕捉します
So the radiation it catches will be even greater
したがって、受ける放射線はさらに大きくなります
so before
だから前に
Then it is the satellite of Safari, Geno
それではサファリの衛星、ジェノです
it
それ
You see it's the dose
線量がわかります
250 times around the lower satellite
衛星下部を250周
So you're testing higher doses like this
つまり、このように高用量をテストしているのです
so it is
それはそうです
a satellite it protects
衛星を保護する
In order to protect the instrument inside it from letting the
中の楽器を守るため、
radiation killed it
放射能が死んだ
it retakes 100
100を取り直す
80 kg like this
80kgならこんな感じ
so it
それはそう
This satellite actually shrinks the outer layer of its instruments
この衛星は実際に機器の外層を縮小します
It is packed with a lot of this very thick this
これがたっぷり詰まってて分厚いです
stereotype
固定観念
let it not be this
そうならないように
The radiation in this space killed it
この空間の放射線がそれを殺しました
But this is what I just said
しかし、これは私が今言ったことです
We usually in the satellite development process
私たちは通常、衛星の開発プロセスに携わっています。
We need a lot of this semo cycle
このセモサイクルがたくさん必要です
I put this thing
こんなものを置きました
The whole instrument cools it down
楽器全体が冷える
depends on the orbit of your satellite
衛星の軌道によって異なります
Usually if it is in an orbit relatively close to the earth
通常、地球に比較的近い軌道にある場合
probably will be in
おそらく入っているでしょう
Temperature between plus 50 degrees and minus 50 degrees
気温はプラス50度からマイナス50度の間
just let it do the loop
ただループさせてください
Of course because in space it is
もちろん宇宙ですから
It's a complete vacuum so you vacuum up the whole instrument
完全な真空なので、楽器全体を真空にします。
then heat it inside
それから中で加熱します
or cooling heating cooling
または冷却加熱冷却
then keep watching
それから見続けてください
see if there is any problem with it
それに問題があるかどうかを確認してください
Then there is the so-called vibration
それからいわゆる振動があります
This is the instrument we made before
これは私たちが以前作った楽器です
failure example
失敗例
Actually it's this
実はこれなんです
We put the instrument on a vibrating table
振動台の上に楽器を置きます
Then it will simulate the vibration when launching
起動時の振動をシミュレートします
After finishing, my board fell off
終わった後、ボードが落ちてしまいました。
because when we design
なぜなら私たちがデザインするとき
it's in the process of processing
処理中です
It's just the design
それはただのデザインです
But when processing
しかし、加工するときに、
it will generate some
それはいくつかを生成します
I said that the hard power is on this board
この板にはハードパワーがあると言いました
so it breaks when you shake too much
あまり振ると壊れてしまうので
So these vibrating
それで、これらは振動しています
all design matters
すべてのデザインが重要
Letting you equal to making your design better
デザインを改善することは、デザインを改善することと同じです
so that it can really stand up to your design
あなたのデザインに本当に耐えられるように
launch all questions
すべての質問を開始する
So there will be no problem when actually launching
なので実際に起動する際には問題ありません
It can be launched smoothly
スムーズに起動できる
in this way
この上
It's actually pretty cool to watch this launch.
実際、この打ち上げを見るのはかなりクールだ。
is how much it shocks you
それはあなたにどれだけショックを与えますか
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
elliptical orbit satellite
楕円軌道衛星
The place where the lowest ball is the lightest is about 300 kilometers
一番低いボールが一番軽い場所は約300キロ
The farthest place is about 10,000 kilometers
一番遠い所でも約1万キロ
It's all about what we're going to do
すべては私たちが何をするかにかかっている
then what's the point of these things
では、これらのことには何の意味があるのでしょうか
what is his challenge
彼の挑戦は何ですか
we just said you do one thing
私たちはあなたが一つのことをすると言ったところです
I often want to say that angels, righteous people and
私がよく言いたいのは、天使、義人、そして
If you ask me, is there any abandoned development now?
私に言わせれば、現在放棄された開発はありますか？
In fact, I told you everything is not
実際、すべてがそうではないと言った
we are doing this
私たちはこれをやっています
Abandoned development is always true
放棄された開発は常に真実です
It's really a very, very difficult situation right now.
今は本当に、とても、とても難しい状況です。
The first is the astronomical
1つ目は天文学的なものです
I want to say that after the big problem
大問題が終わってから言いたい。
it's all big
それはすべて大きいです
It's all big and he's been developing it for a long time
それはすべて大きく、彼はそれを長い間開発してきました
So now we often joke that
それで今では私たちはよく冗談を言います
you make a plan now
あなたは今計画を立てます
When will you finish this project?
このプロジェクトはいつ終わりますか?
He can finish it when I retire
私が引退したら彼はそれを終えることができる
So you often have a problem
それでよく問題が起きる
It means you do this for a long time
これを長時間やるということは、
when planning for a long time
長期にわたる計画を立てるとき
How do you attract people to invest
どうやって人々を投資に誘うのか
Actually this is a big problem
実はこれは大きな問題なのです
Of course the bigger you do this thing
もちろん、このことを行うのが大きければ大きいほど、
The more money you have
お金が多ければ多いほど
So cross-border cooperation is normal
だから国境を越えた協力は普通のことだ
We are often several countries
私たちはしばしば複数の国です
come and do this together
来て一緒にこれをやりましょう
This is another project we have in Mexico
これは私たちがメキシコで行っているもう一つのプロジェクトです
We're going to this observatory in Mexico
私たちはメキシコのこの天文台に行きます
The Science of Building Three Telescopes to Make This Eye Star
この目を星にするために 3 つの望遠鏡を組み立てる科学
then you will see this snow
そうすればこの雪が見えるでしょう
And then the snow melts and then the snow comes again
そして雪が溶けるとまた雪が降ります
So this plan actually cost
つまり、このプランの実際の費用は
close to our ten years
私たちの10年が近づいてきました
and then it might be about time to start
そして、そろそろ始める時期かもしれない
Our observation work
私たちの観察活動
Ten years in astronomy is pretty normal now
天文学に携わって10年は今ではごく普通のことだ
A number is from starting a project to
数字はプロジェクトの開始から
it can actually start observing
実際に観察を始めることができます
It's not the end of the project but the start of doing what you want to do
プロジェクトは終わりではなく、やりたいことの始まりです
That's like ten years
それは10年ほどです
i just said
私はちょうど言いました
Such multinational projects are also very common
このような多国籍プロジェクトも非常に一般的です
this is mine
これは私のものです
Another sentence that goes on now
今続いているもう一つの文
You can see how many points there are
ポイントが何点あるかがわかります
A point represents a cooperative unit
点は協力ユニットを表します
so you have
それであなたは持っています
Five or six different countries at the same time
同時に 5 ～ 6 か国
come
来て
astronomers come together
天文学者が集まる
work on this development
この開発に取り組む
The biggest problem with this forecast is what to do when I have a meeting
この予測の最大の問題は、会議のときに何をすべきかということです
So usually you are not very early
だから通常はあまり早くない
It's late for a meeting
会議に遅れました
to do this conference call
この電話会議を行うには
this is
これは
Then by the way why the earth is not flat
ところで、なぜ地球は平らではないのか
why the earth is round
なぜ地球は丸いのか
That said
そうは言っても
Speaking of
といえば
I just talked about the angel Nadili
先ほど天使ナディリについて話しました。
Observatories are usually in that kind of shitty place
天文台って大抵あんなクソみたいなところにあるんだな
I just talked about a series of design to consider these issues
これらの問題を考慮した一連の設計についてお話しました。
that work too
その仕事も
This is us in Hawaii, Makia
これがハワイの私たち、マキアです
We have several observatories here
ここには天文台がいくつかあります
I took this photo because our working environment is like this
うちの作業環境がこんな感じなので写真を撮りました
Temperature 1.8C
温度 1.8℃
Relative humidity 14%
相対湿度 14%
The most important thing is this is
最も重要なことはこれです
This is the air pressure is 620%
これは空気圧が620％です
Then we know that the normal ground should be 1000
次に、通常の地面は 1000 である必要があることがわかります。
is about half
約半分です
So the oxygen in your airway over there is
気道内の酸素は
only half of the ground
地面の半分だけ
so usually a
だから通常は
In Gaoshan town and very uncomfortable environment
高山市の非常に不快な環境
I would have liked to put a photo
写真を載せればよかった
After my colleague got to the top, he quickly brought some oxygen up
同僚が頂上に着いた後、すぐに酸素を持ってきてくれました
where to visit
どこを訪れるか
then there is
それからあります
So on this, if you have to do some very heavy work, it is actually very hard
これについては、非常に重労働をしなければならない場合、実際には非常に困難です
This is when I arrived very early
とても早く到着したときです
At that time, I was photographed doing this
その時、こんなことをしているところを写真に撮られました
We need to re-enforce this mirror
このミラーを再強化する必要があります
Therefore, the aluminum of this degree on the entire surface of the mirror should be removed.
したがって、鏡面全体にあるこの程度のアルミニウムを除去する必要がある。
wipe it clean
きれいに拭いてください
it's very very tiring
とてもとても疲れます
you have to take this
これを受け取らなければなりません
This is the last step
これが最後のステップです
So take that gas mask off
だからガスマスクを外してください
you have no oxygen
あなたには酸素がありません
Then you have to wear a gas mask while working
それから仕事中はガスマスクを着用しなければなりません
it's very very hard
とてもとても難しいです
Of course, our colleagues in Grinda are also protected from the cold
もちろん、グリンダの同僚たちも寒さから守られています。
rarely do you see this
めったにこれを見ませんか
Why did he take this photo because he found this
なぜ彼はこれを見つけたのでこの写真を撮ったのか
The temperature of color consciousness is almost the same as Huashi
色彩意識は華師とほぼ同じ温度
Then I knew it was Chinese style and it was about 30 degrees
それからそれが中国風であることがわかりました、そしてそれは約30度でした
It's when it's minus 30 degrees
マイナス30度の時です
When working outside, you have to be fully dressed and there will be no place to show
屋外で作業する場合は、完全な服装をしなければならず、見せる場所はありません。
That person is also the same, our salaries in the war rescue unit are very low
あの人も同じです、戦争救助隊の給料はとても安いです
What we need is, of course, what we need are very experienced engineers
もちろん、私たちが必要としているのは、非常に経験豊富なエンジニアです。
It is very difficult for an experienced engineer, and it is difficult for you to attract him with a salary
経験豊富なエンジニアにとっては非常に困難であり、給与で彼を引き付けるのは困難です
So we usually use, I don't know, we say them, they're cute
だから私たちは通常、「わからない」「かわいいね」と言います。
They just think it's more fun to work here.
彼らはただ、ここで働くほうが楽しいと思っているだけなのです。
Or if they are very interested in me, then they will be willing to join our team
あるいは、彼らが私に非常に興味を持っているなら、喜んで私たちのチームに加わるでしょう。
Then of course we often meet people after they come
もちろん、人が来た後に会うこともよくあります
After a year or two of what he learned, he left
彼は学んだことを1、2年続けた後に去ってしまった
So this is a big problem
これは大きな問題です
He's not just them, even our researcher level is the same
彼らだけじゃない、我々研究者レベルも同じだ
Because I have worn one piece every ten years, and I have a piece of paper when I have worn one piece
だって私は10年に1枚着てて、1枚着たら紙切れがあるんです。
Because of the normal conditions inside, just kick him out
内部は正常な状態なので、彼を追い出してください
This director may be clearer
この監督の方がわかりやすいかもしれない
It is the cooperation of the researchers of the Central Academy of Sciences
中央科学院の研究者の協力によるものです
There are actually some requirements for the number of papers
実は論文数にはいくつかの要件があります
So how are you putting yourself into this kind of work?
それで、あなたはどのようにしてこの種の仕事に身を投じていますか？
It can also maintain the output of your paper
論文の出力を維持することもできます
In fact, it is also a very important question
実は、これも非常に重要な質問です
But I think I've told you so much today
でも、今日はたくさん話せたと思います
I think we've spent the past few years
私たちはここ数年を過ごしてきたと思う
We really did a lot of planning
本当にたくさんの計画を立てました
Cover different this painting glasses
別のこの絵のメガネをカバーします。
Let these systems be installed on the painting glasses
これらのシステムを塗装ガラスに取り付けてみましょう
and then be able to play their role
そして自分の役割を果たせるようになる
It is important to hope that they can make
彼らが成功できることを期待することが重要です
Astronomers in Taiwan can use these
台湾の天文学者はこれらを使用できます
The instruments we made
私たちが作った楽器たち
Then do the most cutting-edge astronomical research like this
そして、このような最先端の天文学研究を行ってください
then we just started
それから私たちは始まったばかりです
the beast talked about
獣が話した
We are now at least two major projects that I am working on
現在、少なくとも 2 つの主要プロジェクトに取り組んでいます
one is
一つは
Speaker's astronomy satellite
講演者の天文衛星
This is an infrared astronomy satellite
これは赤外線天文衛星です
It is a big project of cooperation between Europe and Japan
ヨーロッパと日本の協力による一大プロジェクトです
To send a 2.5-meter astronomical satellite into space
2.5メートルの天文衛星を宇宙に飛ばすには
It operates at a lower temperature
より低い温度で動作します
Its entire system is 8K
システム全体が8Kです
8K is minus -265 degrees
8Kはマイナス-265度です
Almost the brightest mirror connection you can achieve
実現可能なほぼ最も明るいミラー接続
We have already begun to design some instruments in this part
この部分ではすでにいくつかの機器の設計を開始しています
This is tantamount to our first project to compare large and astronomical satellites
これは、大型衛星と天文衛星を比較するという私たちの最初のプロジェクトに相当します。
So what we're doing now isn't...
それで、私たちが今やっていることはそうではありません...
Participation is not too big
参加人数はそれほど多くない
But it can provide us scientists to participate in perhaps this first-hand
しかし、それは私たち科学者におそらくこの問題に直接参加する機会を提供します
Infrared Observation Data
赤外線観測データ
The other big project is
もう一つの大きなプロジェクトは、
I just talked about the biggest future...
私は今、最大の未来について話しました...
But the golden king has already reached this EOT in Europe
しかし、黄金の王はすでにヨーロッパのこのEOTにいます
One and the instrument in which we are involved
1 つと私たちが関わっている楽器
Then this series
それからこのシリーズ
I just got back from Holland last week to talk to them
彼らと話すために先週オランダから戻ってきたところです
what parts are we responsible for
私たちがどの部分を担当するのか
Taiwan has done very well because of the processing of some machinery
台湾は一部の機械の加工で非常に好調だった
So we might be responsible for the entire
したがって、私たちはすべての責任を負う可能性があります
core part of a series
シリーズの核となる部分
How big is this series?
このシリーズはどれくらいの大きさですか？
The entire height of this series is approximately
このシリーズの全高は約
2.5 meters
2.5メートル
This width is
この幅は
About 1.5 meters
約1.5メートル
It is easy to put this
これなら入れやすいですね
cover it all
すべてをカバーする
So this is our current
これが私たちの現在です
Next
次
key work items
主要な作業項目
so today i
だから今日私は
It is very simple to introduce to you our Tianwen
私たちの天文を紹介するのは非常に簡単です
instruments of these
これらの楽器
and some
いくつかの
details then
詳細はそれで
some key points
いくつかの重要なポイント
The conclusion is that we really need a lot of different talents
結論としては、本当にさまざまな才能が必要だということです
Of course, at the same time, our technology does not mean that we can do it ourselves.
もちろん、私たちの技術があるからといって、それが自分たちでできるわけではありません。
In fact, there are also cooperation with many domestic manufacturers
実は国内メーカーも多数提携しております
We also undertake some cases of manufacturers to help them do some system development
メーカー様のシステム開発をお手伝いする案件も一部お引き受けしております。
The hope is that in addition to building our own technology
独自の技術を構築するだけでなく、
It can also help some domestic industries like this
このような一部の国内産業にも役立ちます
Our astronomical institute was actually able to participate in these important international projects in the past
私たちの天文学研究所は、実際に過去にこれらの重要な国際プロジェクトに参加することができました。
In fact, it has a very important correlation with our technological crisis.
実際、それは私たちの技術的危機と非常に重要な相関関係があります。
That's the end of my speech today. Thank you.
今日の私のスピーチはこれで終わります。ありがとうございました。
Thank you, Mr. Wang, for your wonderful speech.
王さん、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました。
At that time, I heard that there are actually people stationed in Hawaii in our courtyard.
その時、実は我が家の中庭にハワイに駐在している人がいると聞きました。
At that time, my small mind was probably in YTB
あの時、私の小さな心はYTBにあったのかもしれない
Wow, that's too much, I want to say that life is ashamed, couples play together
うわー、それは多すぎる、人生は恥ずかしいと言いたい、カップルは一緒に遊ぶ
Is it okay? Later I found out that they were in Monaca.
大丈夫ですか? 後で知ったのですが、モナカにあったんです。
Mona seems to be that Hawaii
モナはあのハワイらしい
That Monaca seems to be
あのモナカはそうです
In fact, Mona actually means three in Hawaii.
実はモナとはハワイ語で「3」を意味します。
So in the original there is still in Lulan
原作ではまだルーランにいるんですね
I heard that wow it looks like a lot in Greenland
すごいことはグリーンランドによく似ていると聞いた
great place still up
素晴らしい場所はまだ残っています
The colleagues at the astronomical institute really worked hard
天文研究所の仲間たちは本当によく頑張りました
Then everyone knows that in the Chinese Academy
中国アカデミーでは誰もがそれを知っています
Let's just say that the research pressure is unbelievable again.
研究のプレッシャーが再び信じられないほどであるとだけ言っておきましょう。
So that one said it would take ten years to build an observatory
天文台を建てるには10年かかると言ったそうです
Everyone knows that we are researchers
私たちが研究者であることは誰もが知っています
About five or six years will be renewed
5～6年程度の更新となります
Then if your academic research
学術研究であれば
There is no way to publish a good paper
良い論文を出版する方法はない
soon you probably will
すぐにあなたもそうするでしょう
So this research is incredibly stressful.
したがって、この研究は非常にストレスがかかります。
no matter what
何があっても
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
What about us today, we have prepared some small gifts
今日はどうでしょうか、ちょっとしたプレゼントをご用意しました
That is whether the presence is aimed at everyone
それはその存在がすべての人に向けられているかどうか
Teacher Wang's wonderful speech
王先生の素晴らしいスピーチ
do you have any questions
何か質問がありますか
Then if you report your name first
じゃあ先に名前を報告すれば
Then there is your question, thank you
それではご質問です、ありがとうございます
After all Huang Qifang I am Datong
やっぱり黄奇芳、私は大同です
I just learned that our
今知ったのですが、私たちの
Sensor for astronomical images
天体画像用センサー
The resolution is actually 10 times lower than that of a mobile phone
解像度は実際には携帯電話の10分の1です
10 micro meters and one micro meter
10マイクロメートルと1マイクロメートル
Its pixel size is right
ピクセルサイズは適切です
Then such a large optical lens is 10 meters
そうすると、このような大きな光学レンズは10メートルになります
20 meters 30 meters
20メートル 30メートル
so much information
とてもたくさんの情報
It seems a bit wasteful to use such a thick Sensor
こんな厚いセンサー使うのはちょっともったいない気がする
Then I was wondering if there is a possibility
そこで可能性があるのではないかと考えたのですが、
I'm a professor in the Department of Electrical Engineering
私は電気工学科の教授です
Sensor of current commercial camera
現在市販されているカメラのセンサー
Tens of millions of pixels
数千万ピクセル
Maybe its environmental quality
おそらくその環境品質
Cannot meet the needs of astronomy
天文学のニーズに応えられない
Is it possible to use these small Sensors in the future?
将来的にこれらの小型センサーを使用することは可能ですか?
so high resolution
とても解像度が高い
Multiply it into an Array
配列にする
Because I just heard that there is a combination of Sensors
センサーの組み合わせがあると聞いたので
just a few hundred million
ほんの数億
Then it may be tens of millions if you use this one like Sony.
そうするとソニーみたいにこれ使うと数千万かかるかもしれない。
Tens of millions in a small street
小さな通りに数千万人
That pocket may be worth billions or tens of billions
大きなポケットは数十億または数百億になる可能性があります
Is it possible
出来ますか
I may not have said a word just now
今は何も言っていなかったかもしれない
That's why we choose 10 microns
それが私たちが 10 ミクロンを選択する理由です
When our pixel size
私たちのピクセルサイズが
actually because
実際、なぜなら
It's because of the big old hole I just mentioned
それは先ほど言った大きな古い穴のせいです
That’s my optical theory. I can make this optical machine very small.
これが私の光学理論であり、この光学機械は非常に小さくすることができます。
Put the dot machine very small
ドットマシンを非常に小さく置きます
But because of this atmospheric old hole relationship
でもこの雰囲気ある古穴関係のせいで
So my dots get bigger
だから私の点は大きくなる
Then I don't use a small sensor when the light spot becomes bigger
光点が大きくなると小さなセンサーは使わなくなります
that pitch
そのピッチ
to cover it because
それをカバーするため
Each pixel will have a noise when read out
読み出すと各ピクセルにノイズが発生します
so
それで
We will choose the size of this sensor which is about 10 microns
このセンサーのサイズは約10ミクロンを選択します
Of course I just said that if you use that
もちろん、それを使用する場合はそう言っただけです
that
それか
modulated optics i can get this quality right
変調光学、この品質を正しく得ることができます
At that time we usually
そのとき私たちは通常、
use
用
different way
違う方法
to lengthen the focal length of my optics
光学系の焦点距離を長くするには
let it Play Scale
スケールをプレイしてみましょう
is the field of view per unit length
単位長さあたりの視野です
let it change
変えてみましょう
Of course in astronomy
もちろん天文学でも
why do i seem to say
なぜ私がそう言っているようですか
Like I'm talking about 10 micro
10マイクロについて話しているような
This pixel doesn't seem to change
このピクセルは変わっていないように見えます
The main reason is that
主な理由は、
In developing these astronomy-specific
これらの天文学特有の開発においては、
There are very few companies with this sensor
このセンサーを搭載している企業は非常に少ないです
This is what we use on our phone
これは私たちが電話で使っているものです
This sensor is related to our own
このセンサーは当社独自のものです
The sensor we use for astronomy
天文学に使用されるセンサー
The biggest difference is
最大の違いは
Sensitivity of the mobile phone
携帯電話の感度
The functionality of the sensor is only about 50%
センサーの機能は50％程度しかありません
good about one percent
1パーセントくらいは良い
Usually about 20 to 30 percent
だいたい20～30パーセントくらい
More than 90% of the astronomy was used that day
その日、天文学の90％以上が使用されました
Then this is related to it, the structure is not the same
そうすると、これはそれに関連していますが、構造は同じではありません
that is
あれは
Slowly, the current sensor of the mobile phone
ゆっくりと携帯電話の電流センサー
also gradually changed to
も徐々に変わってきました
what we call preparation
私たちが準備と呼ぶもの
It's light coming in from the back
後ろから光が入ってきます
Because there are many circuits on the Sensor
センサーには多くの回路があるため
These circuits will
これらの回路は、
because it blocks the light
光を遮るので
So you can't increase its sensitivity
だから感度を上げることはできない
Then when you go in from the back
そして後ろから入ると
it can increase a lot
たくさん増える可能性があります
But this back cover
しかしこの裏表紙
Sensor is
センサーは
At least CMOS is the Sensor of all our mobile phones
少なくともCMOSはすべての携帯電話のセンサーです
It has only gradually become popular in the past two years
ここ2年ほどで徐々に普及してきました
I just mentioned
先ほども言いましたが
We have a big camera with this CMOS
このCMOSを搭載した大きなカメラがあります
That Sensor was actually at the beginning
そのセンサーは実は最初にあった
We all ask TSMC or UMC to ask them to do
私たちは皆、TSMC または UMC に次のことを依頼します。
say no
ダメって言って
because they asked
彼らが尋ねたから
large market
市場多大
I said maybe 100 pills a year
年間100錠くらいって言ってた
then he said goodbye
それから彼は別れを告げた
So these requirements of astronomy
したがって、天文学のこれらの要件は
How can I follow
どうすればフォローできますか
with average
平均的な
We still follow the general needs of the industry
私たちは依然として業界の一般的なニーズに従っています
there is a big difference
大きな違いがあります
That's unless the two of them can get close
それは二人が近づけなければ
We have the means to convince these companies
私たちはこれらの企業を説得する手段を持っています
they can invest
彼らは投資できる
in this way
この上
Otherwise, it would still be very expensive for us to do
そうしないと、依然として非常に費用がかかることになります
one
一位
My surname is Huang
私の姓は黄です
just be
ちょうどであること
just like i see that
私がそれを見ているのと同じように
It is when the live broadcast is when the black hole is live broadcast
ブラックホールが生放送のときは生放送のときです
It seems that you will practice that kind of self-discipline
そんな自戒を込めて練習するそうですよ
The kind of manufacturers you mentioned just now, cooperation, etc.
今おっしゃったメーカーの種類、協力関係等。
then i see
それならわかります
I see Zhonggang, Zhonglong
中崗、中龍が見えます
Then everyone kept writing
それからみんな書き続けた
Then it seems that in this so-called
それから、このいわゆる
The cooperation between the instrument and the manufacturer
機器とメーカーの協力
it becomes as if the communication above
上の通信のようになります
Because this is a very professional kind of astronomy
これは非常に専門的な天文学であるため、
Then their kind as far as we know
それから、我々が知る限り彼らの種類は
Probably some heavy industrial equipment
おそらく重工業用の機器でしょう
Between these two, between you and the manufacturer
この 2 つの間、あなたとメーカーの間
Because it's still about astronomy
まだ天文学の話だから
the specialized part
専門的な部分
because what you want
あなたが望むものだから
communication between them
彼らの間のコミュニケーション
does it become
なるのか？
Can I get a general idea?
一般的なアイデアを得ることができますか?
That's a good question
それは良い質問です
Why we need our own engineers
自社のエンジニアが必要な理由
just because we need to do it
それをする必要があるから
or me too
あるいは私も
I want to understand the needs of astronomy
天文学のニーズを理解したい
that understands the norms of astronomy
天文学の規範を理解している
Then you can communicate with the manufacturer
その後、メーカーと通信できます
when i do this now
今これをするとき
I don't want to use the traditional way
従来の方法は使いたくない
what do i want to change
私は何を変えたいですか
what do i need
私が必要なものは何
I didn't talk carefully just now
今は慎重に話さなかった
In fact, many of our mechanical processing
実際、当社の機械加工の多くは
The accuracy we want is one or two
私たちが求める精度は 1 か 2 です
That is, its machining accuracy is very, very high.
つまり、加工精度が非常に高いのです。
One is one-tenth the width of a hair
1本は髪の毛の10分の1の幅です
So when your team has these concepts
したがって、チームがこれらのコンセプトを持っていると、
And then it itself comes from industry acceptance
そしてそれ自体が業界で受け入れられることによって生まれます
It has a way to go back and communicate with people in this industry
過去に戻ってこの業界の人々とコミュニケーションをとる方法がある
What do I want
私が欲しいものは
Then how can you possibly achieve
それではどうすれば達成できるでしょうか
what i want
私が欲しいもの
Just like we developed the Sensor
私たちがセンサーを開発したのと同じように
Because I am the background of Sensor
センサーの背景は私だから
I can communicate with the manufacturer about what I want
欲しいものについてメーカーとコミュニケーションが取れる
what kind of circuit
どのような回路ですか
this one
これです
Hello, Dr. Wang, my name is Lin
こんにちは、王博士、私の名前はリンです。
i want to ask two questions
2つの質問がしたいです
The first is to say that in the development of so-called astronomical instruments
1 つ目は、いわゆる天文機器の開発において、
Not in the development of science graduate instruments
理系大学院機器の開発ではない
What disciplines does it really need?
本当に必要な学問は何でしょうか?
Then what is its cultivation and source usually like?
では、その栽培と供給源は通常どのようになっているのでしょうか？
Then the second question is that in a complete astronomical observation program
次に 2 番目の質問は、完全な天体観測プログラムでは
The role of the so-called scientist is, for example,
いわゆる科学者の役割は、例えば次のとおりです。
astronomer or physicist throughout the program
プログラム全体を通じて天文学者または物理学者
What parts of the work does it participate in and what role does it play
それは仕事のどの部分に参加し、どのような役割を果たしますか
Thanks
ありがとう
we need all kinds of people
私たちはあらゆる種類の人々を必要としています
So in our
ですから私たちの中では
we have optical engineers
私たちには光学エンジニアがいます
we have mechanical engineers
私たちには機械エンジニアがいます
we have microwave engineers
私たちにはマイクロ波エンジニアがいます
Electronic function engineer Software function engineer
電子機能エンジニア ソフトウェア機能エンジニア
And the function engineer of the detector
そして検出器の機能エンジニア
So you can basically what I just mentioned
したがって、基本的には今述べたことを行うことができます
Each part has a corresponding functional division
各部分には対応する機能部門があります
come and go take care of these things
行ったり来たり、これらのことを世話してください
Because we can't buy anything we touch
触るものは買えないから
I even had to design the circuit myself
自分で回路を設計する必要もありました
Then clean the factory to wash
その後、工場を洗浄して洗浄します
Then come back and call yourself like this
それから戻ってきて、自分自身をこのように呼んでください
So basically these things are
基本的にこれらのことは次のとおりです
all needed
すべて必要な
The second question just said
2番目の質問は今言いました
about the role of astronomers in observing
観測における天文学者の役割について
Basically after we finish the instrument
基本的に楽器が完成した後
Astronomers will see that
天文学者はそれを見るでしょう
There is one more instrument on the earphone side that can be used
イヤホン側に使える楽器がもう一つあります
They are going to explain the characteristics of this instrument
この楽器の特徴を説明してもらいます
We usually do some tests
私たちは通常、いくつかのテストを行います
We put the instruments behind the observatory
天文台の後ろに計器を置きます
will start testing its basic features
基本機能のテストを開始します
These properties will have a table
これらのプロパティにはテーブルが含まれます
or have a system that can do the calculations
または計算できるシステムがある
That day the astronomer based on what he thought
あの日、天文学者は自分の考えに基づいて
he will calculate
彼は計算してくれるでしょう
i want to see this celestial body
この天体を見たい
How much observation time may I need
どれくらいの観察時間が必要ですか
Then he will start writing his observation plan.
それから彼は観察計画を書き始めます。
the observation program
観察プログラム
If after the observation time
観察時間を過ぎた場合
The weather is great
天気は素晴らしいです
he gets his information
彼は自分の情報を入手します
After getting the information
情報を入手してから
he's going to deal with it
彼はそれに対処するつもりだ
That deals with the usual words
それは通常の言葉を扱います
Every instrument he might have
彼が持っているかもしれないあらゆる楽器
meeting
ミーティング
when we send the instrument out
楽器を発送するとき
we will have
私たちは持っています
Follow his data processing system
彼のデータ処理システムをフォローしてください
so he can use
だから彼は使える
The data processing systems we provide
当社が提供するデータ処理システム
to process his data
彼のデータを処理するために
Then do more follow-up analysis
その後、さらに追跡分析を行います
or
また
If he feels that he handles these data
自分がこれらのデータを扱っていると感じる場合
he is sure of himself
彼は自分に自信がある
He can also do his own data processing
彼は独自のデータ処理も行うことができます
Then do the following analysis
次に、次の分析を実行します
Then the subsequent analysis may be very
その後の分析は非常に重要になる可能性があります
there is a big difference
大きな違いがあります
I may be doing statistics
統計をやっているのかもしれない
I might just do this for a single celestial body
単一の天体に対してこれを行うだけかもしれません
Analysis of characteristics
特性的分析
that makes a big difference
それは大きな違いを生む
that is
あれは
real astronomer
本物の天文学者
or astrophysical systems they
または天体物理システム
they are really professional
彼らは本当にプロフェッショナルです
ok this sir
わかりました、先生
Hello, I am a believer. Let me continue with the question you just answered.
こんにちは、信者です。先ほどお答えいただいた質問の続きをさせていただきます。
I want to know, the world is currently full of information to say
知りたい、今世界には言いたい情報が溢れている
no one to analyze or say this
これを分析したり言ったりする人は誰もいません
Every astronomer is waiting for that Q to say I want this data
すべての天文学者は、Q がこのデータが欲しいと言ってくるのを待っています。
got it a year later
一年後に手に入れた
This is where astronomers have two
ここで天文学者は 2 つの意見を持っています。
If you ask our director, he will say that there are too many materials
ディレクターに聞くと、資料が多すぎると言うでしょう
If you go to check it casually, it will be the taper that can produce an infinite amount of taper every year.
何気なくチェックしに行ったら、毎年無限にテーパーを生み出せるテーパーです。
In fact, there is a lot of data
実はデータがたくさんあるんです
Data that has been observed at various observatories
さまざまな天文台で観測されたデータ
That of course means that there are many problems
ということは、もちろん問題もたくさんあるということです
Or there are many specialized subjects
あるいは専門科目が多い
It needs new instruments to have a way to break through
突破口を開くには新しい手段が必要だ
There is a way to go. For example, I want to see the universe farther away.
たとえば、もっと遠くの宇宙を見てみたい。
Then I couldn't get this far before, I couldn't
それから、以前はここまで到達できなかった、できなかった
So there are two very different kinds of this
したがって、これには 2 つのまったく異なる種類があります
The path of research looks like this
研究の道はこんな感じ
right
右
Are there any special requirements for the material of the lens?
レンズの材質に特別な要件はありますか?
Is the radius of that area ground by yourself?
その辺の半径は自分で削るのでしょうか？
Well
良い
In most of the development of astronomical instruments
天文機器の開発のほとんどにおいて
The research unit does not grind the lens itself
研究ユニットはレンズ自体を研磨しません
few have
持っている人はほとんどいません
In fact, we rely a lot on
実際、私たちは以下に大きく依存しています
These relatively specialized optical manufacturers
これらの比較的専門的な光学メーカー
For example, there is a quite large factory in France
たとえば、フランスにかなり大きな工場があります。
Then Japan like Kallang or Nikon
それなら日本はカランとかニコンとか
they are also very useful
それらもとても便利です
those materials
それらの材料
Visible light materials are usually relatively fixed
可視光材料は通常比較的固定されています
and easier to get
そして入手しやすくなります
The market for this is huge
この市場は巨大です
the infrared words
赤外線の言葉
so it's more difficult for me
だから私にとってはもっと難しいです
The problem I've found that I often run into is saying
私がよく遭遇する問題は、次のようなことです。
I now need a lens like 30cm
30cmくらいのレンズが必要になりました
But you ask the whole world to tell you
でもあなたは全世界にそう言ってほしいと頼む
no, no one produces
いや、誰も作ってないよ
Not the lens, just the material
レンズではなく素材だけです
There is no such a large material
そんな大きな資料は無い
So then you have to think of other ways to break through
だったら別の突破方法を考える必要がある
For example, if I divide a speed of light into
たとえば、光の速度を次のように分割すると、
34 light speeds like this
34光速はこんな感じ
to do different designs
さまざまなデザインを行う
Let me ask Mr. Wang first
まずは王さんに聞いてみましょう
Mainland China because about last year I knew they were going to build a 500-meter-diameter one
中国本土、というのは昨年くらいに直径500メートルのものが建設されると知っていたからだ。
Yes, I asked at the beginning
はい、最初に質問しました
Then I know it seems that he is better than the original
そうしたら、どうやら彼はオリジナルよりも優れているようです
It turns out that it seems to be only about 100 or 200
どうやら100か200くらいしかないようだ
diameter 300
直径300
Then his main purpose
それから彼の主な目的は
And that class should be very high
そしてそのクラスは非常に高いはずです
That is, we usually say that the requirements of this mirror are closely related to its wavelength.
つまり、通常、このミラーの要件はその波長と密接に関係していると言われます。
This is what I just showed
これが私が今見せたものです
their big eyes
彼らの大きな目は
this is 500 meters
ここは500メートルです
Then his main thing
それから彼の主なことは
The wavelength of the tube car
チューブカーの波長
The wavelength of this antenna tube car is
このアンテナ管車の波長は
possibly centimeter-scale waves
おそらくセンチメートルスケールの波
electromagnetic waves
電磁波
Then his request is like
それから彼のリクエストは次のようなものです
we do
私たちはそうします
Chihavanibo
チハバニボ
or visible light
または可視光線
ask for this
これを頼む
The superficial requirements are much worse
表面的な要件ははるかに悪いです
So the wavelength of my surface is directly proportional to
したがって、私の表面の波長は次のように正比例します。
So let's say I can see light
それで光が見えるとしましょう
I have superficial progress requirements
表面的な進歩の要件がある
This is what we call the Nami rating.
それがいわゆるお米の等級です
maybe a hundred rice
米百個かもしれない
50-resistant rice
五十耐米
That's because the wavelength of my optics is
それは私の光学系の波長が
hundreds of nanometers
何百もの米
so if i
それで私なら
He is centimeter grade
彼はセンチメートル級です
So he superficially asked to become Homi
それで彼は表面的に保見になりたいと頼んだ
Relatively speaking, the difficulty
相対的に難易度を言うと、
not that high
そんなに高くない
Of course it's because he's big
もちろん大きいからね
but this
しかしこれは
You said you want to make the optics so big
光学系をこんなに大きくしたいって言ってたね
This is very currently not possible
これは現時点では非常に不可能です
Let me ask you again, how much will it cost to burn?
もう一度聞きますが、燃やすのにどれくらいの費用がかかりますか？
this is okay
これは大丈夫です
this is what we say
これが私たちが言うことです
that
それか
i was there last week
私は先週そこにいました
To him it's actually
彼にとってそれは実は
His reason is that the wavelength is very long
彼の理由は波長がとても長いからです
that metal piece on his face
彼の顔の金属部分
It's full of holes
穴だらけだよ
Because of him, everything you say is true.
彼のおかげで、あなたの言うことはすべて真実になります。
It's very heavy with a solid piece of metal
しっかりした金属でとても重いです
He said it was full of holes
穴だらけだと言っていた
full of holes
穴だらけ
I mean, if we look from the bottom up
つまり、下から見てみると
Nothing seems to be transparent
何も透明に見えない
it's a lot of holes
穴がたくさんあるよ
he is whole he is whole he is string
彼は完全だ 彼は完全だ 彼はひもだ
There are six towers outside
外には6つの塔があります
His whole string is on it
彼の弦全体がそこに載っています
They develop a new kind of steel wire
彼らは新しい種類の鋼線を開発しました
can lift it all up
すべてを持ち上げることができる
The quality of the steel wire is very good
鋼線の品質は非常に良いです
can hold a lot of weight
たくさんの重量に耐えることができます
What bridge is that pig
あの豚は何の橋ですか
What is it called Hong Kong Pig Harbor?
香港ピッグハーバーとは何ですか?
Hong Kong-Macau Bridge
香港マカオ橋
the line hanging above
上に垂れ下がっているライン
developed from them
それらから発展した
They have body patents
彼らはボディ特許を持っています
that's all
それで全部です
hang on
ちょっとまって
he spent money
彼はお金を使った
i don't know how much it costs
いくらかかるか分かりません
But after spending money like this
でも、こうやってお金を使ってしまうと、
after covering
カバーした後
Their tourism business developed to
彼らの観光事業は次のように発展しました。
money earned from tourism
観光で稼いだお金
More money than the telescope he built
彼が作った望遠鏡よりもお金が多い
So he now covers a lot outside
それで彼は今、屋外で多くのことをカバーしています
the big hotel
大きなホテル
so let's see
それでは見てみましょう
look at you
あなたを見て
top middle
上中
there is one that can
できるものがあります
There can be a table inside
中にテーブルも置ける
you can go up and see
上がって見ることができます
You can go outside for sightseeing
屋外に観光に出かけることもできます
not below
以下ではない
can't go down
下に行けない
because of our
私たちのせいで
our sky school
私たちの空の学校
we can only be below
私たちは下にいるしかない
next to that plate
その皿の隣に
We can't take pictures like this
このような写真は撮れません
I take a photo with my phone
携帯電話で写真を撮ります
According to
によると
only on that plate
その皿の上だけ
about a quarter
約4分の1
We can't take such a panorama
こんなパノラマは撮れない
It must be this. I don’t know how they take pictures.
きっとこれでしょう。どうやって写真を撮っているのかわかりません。
I remember taking pictures is worth billions of RMB
写真を撮るのに数十億人民元の価値があるのを覚えています
billions of RMB
数十億人民元
at the last meeting
最後の会議で
classmate
同級生
He said he would find a few more to develop tourism
彼は観光業を発展させるためにさらにいくつかの方法を見つけるだろうと述べた
In astronomy, he can only do specific astronomy
天文学では特定の天文学しかできない
So he is not a very broad
だから彼はあまり幅広い人ではない
ok ok sorry
分かった、分かった、ごめんなさい
At least solve my confusion
少なくとも私の混乱を解決してください
Because a lot of people are talking about it
たくさんの人が話題にしてるから
Is there another Mr.
他にMr.はいますか？
Hello, Professor Wang, my name is Jin
こんにちは、王教授、私の名前はジンです。
i want to ask
聞きたいです
What kind of environment is restricted in our country
我が国ではどのような環境が制限されているのか
Is it the land spirit or what?
土地の精霊か何かでしょうか？
Why is that very large observatory
なぜあんなに大きな天文台なのか
are abroad
海外にいる
because of the old dimension
古い次元のせいで
our care for the environment
環境への配慮
should not lose to other
他人に負けてはいけない
places like nuclear camp
核収容所のような場所
i think you just walked outside
あなたはちょうど外を歩いていたと思います
you see us rain
私たちに雨が降っているのが見えますね
Extinguish
消火
So Taiwan's problem is
つまり台湾の問題は
We have typhoon, we have rain, right?
台風も来ていますし、雨も降っていますね。
It rains all winter in northern Taiwan
台湾北部では冬の間ずっと雨が降ります
Then there will be beautiful rain and spring rain
そうすれば美しい雨と春の雨が降るでしょう
Well, the weather station, we now know it's probably
そうですね、気象観測所、おそらくそうなることがわかりました
It's a high mountain, near Yushan
玉山の近くの高い山です
There is no way to go to Yushan
玉山へ行く道はない
Yushan has no way to go up
玉山には登る道がない
So some people may say that Yushan may
だから玉山はそうなるかもしれないと言う人もいるかもしれない。
The observation conditions are very good
観察条件は非常に良好です
But there's really no way to get there
でも実際にはそこに行く方法はない
that so
まあまあ
in east asia
東アジアで
To be honest, there isn't any table with a good temperature
正直に言うと、温度の良いテーブルはありません
is east asia
東アジアです
Usually because of this circulation
通常、この循環のせいで
It's all on this side of the ocean
すべては海のこちら側にある
is dry
乾いています
is the Pacific Ocean
太平洋です
on the right is
右側は
is dry left is dead
乾いています 左は死んでいます
for the Atlantic Ocean
大西洋に向けて
so good weather deck
とても良い天気のデッキ
Hawaii is an exception
ハワイは例外
Hawaii because it is in
ハワイにあるから
It's an island protruding from the middle of the ocean
海の真ん中に突き出た島です
So basically the airflow is very stable
基本的にエアフローは非常に安定しています
Then the clouds are all under the mountain
それから雲はすべて山の下にあります
Its mountain is very high, Jade Mountain is still high
その山は非常に高い、翡翠山はまだ高い
So there is no problem above
ですので上記は問題ありません
that's usually good when otherwise
それ以外の場合は通常それで良いです
on the right side of the ocean
海の右側で
That is, when he melts, there will be
つまり、彼が溶けるとき、
he doesn't melt well
彼はうまく溶けない
But he doesn't have summer when you go
でもあなたが行っても彼には夏がない
It was probably zero when I went there in July.
私が7月に行ったときはおそらくゼロでした。
right
右
He probably asked about the humidity
おそらく湿度について尋ねたのだろう
But usually it's pretty dry most of the time
でも、普段はかなり乾燥していることが多いです
is our relative humidity
私たちの相対湿度です
the amount of water vapor in the air
空気中の水蒸気の量
It has a lot to do with temperature
気温も大きく関係してるよ
the more you... the higher the temperature
多ければ多いほど...温度が高くなります
air water content
空気中の水分含有量
I'm not talking about humidity now
今は湿度のことを話しているのではありません
It is the amount of water in the air
空気中の水分量です
opposite to temperature
温度とは逆の
This is when the temperature is lower
この時期は気温が低いので
less water content
水分含有量が少ない
Okay, is there any speech for today's teacher Wang?
さて、今日の王先生に何かスピーチはありますか？
is there any doubt
何か疑問はありますか
All right, man, because we still have a few minutes
わかった、まだ数分あるから
that give him the mic thanks
彼にマイクを渡してくれてありがとう
It seems that there is a slide show about when the old Dong
昔のドンの頃のスライドショーがあるようです。
Doesn't that lens follow that
あのレンズはそれを踏襲してるんじゃないの
Yeah
うん
What method is used to comply with this rapid change
この急激な変化にどのような方法で対応するのか
Is it supposed to be a mechanical way?
それは機械的な方法であるはずですか？
it's the mechanical way
それは機械的な方法です
It's a mechanical way, yes
それは機械的な方法です、はい
When we make this instrument
この楽器を作るとき
It is we have a device called the Wayfram Sensor
Wayframセンサーと呼ばれるデバイスがあります
that is to say this thing
つまりこのことを言うのです
It can detect how my wavefront has changed
私の波面がどのように変化したかを検出できます
Then I was able to control it's drive behind this mirror
その後、このミラーの後ろでドライブを制御することができました
to allow very small changes to the surface of this mirror
このミラーの表面に非常に小さな変化を許可するため
Because this mirror is very, very thin
この鏡はとてもとても薄いので
so it's thin
だから薄いです
The drive won't break when it's moving around behind it
ドライブが後ろで動き回っても壊れません
Can move hundreds of times per second
1秒間に何百回も動くことができる
This is what we call deformable mirror
これが変形可能ミラーと呼ばれるものです
This is a special technique
これは特別なテクニックです
No one in Taiwan should be interested in this
台湾では誰もこんなことに興味ないはず
But it can move very fast
しかし、非常に速く動くことができる
This thing is actually very interesting
これは実際非常に興味深いものです
It was actually developed from a new war plan.
それは実際には新しい戦争計画から開発されました。
Americans in the 1980s
1980年代のアメリカ人
In order to send lasers into outer space to attack artificial satellites
レーザーを宇宙空間に飛ばして人工衛星を攻撃するため
He also needs to fix atmospheric labor
大気労働も修正する必要がある
Otherwise, they went out and said that there is no way to pile them up at one point.
そうでないと、一箇所に積み上げることはできないと言いました。
The lasers have to gather at one point to destroy this thing
これを破壊するにはレーザーが一点に集まる必要がある
So they went to develop the technology
そこで彼らはテクノロジーの開発に着手しました
Then I returned the new battle plan after the end
そして終了後に新たな戦闘計画を戻しました
After hearing about it, he was very happy to say that this thing is very useful.
それを聞いた彼は、これはとても便利だととても喜んでくれました。
just use it
ただ使ってください
Yes because in fact it
はい、実際にそうなので
I'm exaggerating
誇張してます
In fact, its animal range is very small
実際、その動物範囲は非常に狭いです
Its animal range is also
その動物範囲もまた、
Also Neonometer level
ネオノメーターレベルも
good obviously natural
良い明らかに自然
Astronomy and Natural Physics Research
天文学および自然物理学の研究
Natural Physics Research
天然物理研
Institute of Astrophysics
天体物理学研究所
It is actually a cross-domain integration
実際にはクロスドメイン統合です
Need all aspects
あらゆる側面が必要
You say
あなたは言う
say hello online
オンラインで挨拶する
I want to ask something
聞きたいことがあります
Should be a basic question for you
あなたにとって基本的な質問であるはずです
just to make sure
念のため
So visible light observations
ということで可視光観測
usually at night
通常は夜に
So radio observations are
したがって、電波観測は、
Can it be observed day and night?
昼夜を問わず観察できるのでしょうか？
Yes, it depends on your wavelength
はい、それはあなたの波長によります
That is to say
つまり
So usually when doing astronomical observations
ですから、天体観測をするときは、
Will it observe 24 hours for radio observation?
電波観測は24時間観測するのでしょうか？
If it is like the mainland
本土みたいなら
It can be
かもね
But it's you when the sun comes
でも太陽が来るとき、それはあなたです
This signal from the sun is still serious
太陽からのこの信号はまだ深刻です
so he just said
それで彼はただこう言いました
His time can be longer
彼の時間はもっと長くなる可能性がある
It is radio, for example, the CMT I just mentioned
それは無線です、例えば先ほど言ったCMTです。
May be normal visible light environment
通常の可視光環境である可能性があります
It might close at five o'clock.
5時には閉まってしまうかも知れません。
They might get six or seven
彼らは6つか7つを獲得するかもしれない
So when observing at night
なので、夜に観察するときは、
because I just saw
たった今見たから
That's why he's using a camera or
だからこそ彼はカメラを使ったり、
It's just receiving light anyway
とにかく光を受けているだけです
So he will be like we see with human eyes
それで彼は私たちが人間の目で見るのと同じになるでしょう
Just like photography
写真撮影と同じように
Or is it like we shoot for a long time
それとも長時間撮影する感じですか？
For example, every ten minutes
たとえば、10分ごとに
rerun once
翻映一次
then another ten minutes
それからさらに10分
We usually just look at
私たちは普段ただ見ているだけですが、
how dark i want to see
どれだけ暗いか見てみたい
I do not want
欲しくない
If I say I only need ten minutes
10分しかいらないと言ったら
I can see what he wants
彼が何を望んでいるのかはわかります
I don't want to let him lay for fifteen minutes
彼を15分も寝かせたくない
But it can change his
しかし、それは彼のことを変えることができる
we call integration time
積分時間をと呼びます
just the time to light up
ちょうどライトアップの時間
i open the door
私は、ドアを開けます
Then I let him keep collecting
それから私は彼に集め続けさせました
until the time i want
望む時間まで
then the shutter closes
それからシャッターが閉まります
I read the image
画像を読みました
That is to say, in fact
つまり、実は、
Each observatory has a certain
各天文台には特定の
want to see something
何かを見たい
so right
しっくり来る
No, it's an astronomer
いや、天文学者だよ
oh oh oh
ああああああ
It is the observatory. For example, today is me.
天文台です、例えば今日は私です。
then i want to see
それなら見たいです
Well, let's say 15 signals
信号が 15 個あるとします。
Then 15 minutes may be fine.
それなら15分でもいいかもしれません。
that in addition
それに加えて
So the whole night is just minute by minute
だから一晩中はほんの分ごとに
Um
えーっと
If I have to wait until 15
15時まで待たないといけないなら
Then I keep sending for a minute
それから1分間送信し続けます
then i may my this one
それならこれをあげてもいいですか
I am in this direction and I want to wait for 15
私はこの方向にいます、15時まで待ちたいです
Then I have to wait 20 in the other direction
それなら反対方向で20分待たなければなりません
then i will
それなら私がします
going to change
変わるだろう
So I have to do the math in advance
だから事前に計算しておく必要がある
Good thing I'm in this one
私がこの中にいて良かった
Uh, when the observatory knows this direction
ああ、天文台がこの方向を知っているとき
how long do i have to lay
どれくらい横たわっていればいいですか
Then go to how long you have the angle to lay
次に、横になる角度がどのくらいあるのかに進みます
in this way
この上
that is to say
つまり
if run out
なくなったら
visible light telescope
可視光望遠鏡
there is no way
道はない
Observing the galaxy between the sun and the earth in France
フランスで太陽と地球の間にある銀河を観察
is not a galaxy
銀河ではありません
Just like Mercury or something.
マーキュリーか何かのように。
Uh, of course because the sun and the earth
ああ、もちろん太陽と地球だから
The earth revolves around the sun
地球は太陽の周りを回っています
So what's behind the sun changes
それで太陽の後ろにあるものは変わる
Right, so that means if you use visible light
そうです、つまり、可視光を使用する場合
You can only observe at night, you can only look away
夜しか観察できないし、目をそらすことしかできない
yes yes but because
はいはい、でもだから
The earth revolves around the sun
地球は太陽の周りを回っています
So I can still see in all directions
だから私はまだあらゆる方向を見ることができます
I think it's a different time of year
一年とは違う時期だと思います
I can see the sky in different places
いろんな場所で空が見えます
The sun is not always with the earth
太陽はいつも地球とともにあるわけではない
pointing in the same direction
同じ方向を向いている
Say you are the sun and I am the earth
あなたは太陽、私は地球だと言ってください
I'm looking at my back now, right?
今、自分の背中を見ているんですよね？
i can see this sky now
今この空が見えるよ
Then I arrived three months later I look here
それから3か月後に到着しました、ここを見てみます
I can look over there in three months
3か月あればあそこを見られるよ
Yes, yes, see again
はい、はい、また見てください
i mean
つまり
The galaxies between the sun and the earth
太陽と地球の間にある銀河
oh those stars
ああ、あの星たちよ
Yes, for example, the southern star is very early or very late
はい、たとえば、南の星は非常に早いか、または非常に遅いです
there is still a way
まだ方法はあります
That is, it is at a very small angle from the sun
つまり、太陽から非常に小さな角度にあります。
but that angle is small
でもその角度は小さいです
Still big on astronomical scales
天文学的な規模ではまだ大きい
we can still see
私たちはまだ見ることができます
That is, the range usually taken by astronomy is very small.
つまり、通常、天文学が取り得る範囲は非常に狭いということです。
Yes, like the moon
そう、月のように
Let's say the moon is 0.5 degrees
月の角度が0.5度だとしましょう
0.5 degrees is already a very wide angle for astronomical observation
0.5度は天体観測にとってすでに非常に広角です
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
good
良い
I think I've tuned myself into a play lock
私は自分自身をプレイロックに合わせてしまったと思う
I should study astronomy
天文学を勉強すべきです
Okay, it's about 9 o'clock now
さて、もう9時くらいです
Then thank you, thank you very much, Mr. Wang, today is very exciting
それでは、ありがとう、ありがとう、王さん、今日はとてもエキサイティングです
then let's give him a break too
それなら彼も休ませてあげましょう
So with our warmest applause
それでは、温かい拍手とともに
Thank you Wang Xiaoyu Mr. Wang
ありがとう、王暁宇さん、王さん。
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Then I also tell you
それなら私も言います
announce
announce一下
that the next speech will be given by
次のスピーチは～によって行われるだろうと
this is a plant
これは植物です
Illumination and researcher at the Institute of Parasitology
照明と寄生虫研究所の研究者
he wants to talk
彼は話したいのです
The title of his talk was Exploring the Mysteries of Plant Sexual Reproduction
彼の講演のタイトルは「植物の有性生殖の謎を探る」でした。
At that time, I hope everyone can participate enthusiastically
その時は皆さんも積極的に参加していただければと思います
thank you all thank you today
みなさん、今日もありがとう
I came here among my king, thank you all
私は王の元でここに来ました、皆さんありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, all the guests, for coming to our popular science lecture today.
ゲストの皆様、本日は人気科学講座にご来場いただきまして誠にありがとうございます。
to make the event better
イベントをより良くするために